[Music]
okay
now we are back
what's going on guys welcome to today's
stream
now what we're gonna be doing today guys
we are building the slack clone right so
we have tons of stuff to look forward to
today we have react we have redux and
that's just a few things right we have
style components that's new right we've
always wanted to do style components so
now we're going to do it because why
wait right and we also have firebase
hooks now if you've never used firebase
hooks and you used to hate that user
effect that we used to write today's the
day where everything changes i promise
you guys it's gonna be a lot of fun
right now we don't let any you know
technical hurdles beat us we're gonna
completely crush it we
beat the internet don't ask how i did
that
but we are hopefully back we are here to
stay proper fam let's jump in today
into today's build right if you're not
by the way if you're watching this on
youtube jump over to twitch right which
is actually a really nice viewing
experience it would be a lot clearer for
you if you don't find youtube that great
okay so without further ado guys this is
what we're going to be building today
hope you enjoy it smash the thumbs up
button let's get those likes back up
let's see how far we can get today
without further ado guys check it out
this is what we're building we have full
user authentication we wouldn't expect
anything less right so we're gonna go
ahead and log in and guys just before
anyone asks this is different to the
other slack build okay this is different
we actually have completely rebuilt this
one in a much better way and it uses
redux to power all of this stuff okay so
we got multiple channels over here let's
go ahead and jump into a channel right a
really nice thing about this one is if i
go ahead and say hey guys
check this out scrolls to the bottom
pops the message in right so that's a
nice little feature as well in this one
but let's go ahead and jump into this
build right we have react we have redux
we have styled components right we have
material ui right so over here we have
material ui to go ahead and get these
icons to get the look and feel of the
application and guys we have firebase
hooks now firebase hooks is a hell of a
lot of fun
trust me when you see it today and how i
use it
you're gonna be like you're gonna be
impressed guys it's a lot of fun right
now i want this to be fun i don't want
this to be like a super serious
everything kind of you know we just get
too like
serious about coding right i want it to
be a lot of fun i want you guys to just
sit back relax don't worry too much
about following along in time all i want
you guys to do is have fun be a part of
the papa fam and guys just wanted to
mention that we have two days left in
the sale to jump inside of the papa fam
zero to full stack hero community right
first link in the description make sure
you check it out because after that i'm
gonna close the doors to the community
for a while so we can focus on the
course itself and just treat our you
know the papa fam with some love okay so
make sure you go check it out first link
in the description i think we should
jump into this build guys i think we
should smash the thumbs up
for getting through that pain
and uh let's go ahead and jump into
today's build okay so first thing that
we want to do guys is
go ahead and you want to go and open up
a terminal right the first command you
want to open you want to run is mpx
create react app okay so you want to go
ahead let me make this a little bit
bigger for you guys all right mpx create
react app then you want to drop a name
okay so in this case i'm doing slack
clone youtube and today because we're
using redux we're going to be using the
redux template okay so this is finn
horses love the hairstyle so much i'm
asking my mom if she can cut it like
that appreciate you dude thank you
that's that's very nice of you uh
avnishas when's the spotify players
coming oh i will send that out to
everyone if you guys i know you guys
love this playlist right so it's a lot
of fun and guys i just want to mention
right we're not going to split this
video up in several parts because nobody
enjoys that it's going to be one video
crushing it it's the video you need for
slack
i said it let's do it let's jump into
this all right so firebase first thing
we want to do is go ahead and execute
this command to set up our app right so
we're using create react app today if
you're new to the channel you're going
to learn a hell of a lot today so it's
going to be an interesting one make sure
you have water you make sure your coffee
everything ready okay so this will go
ahead set up a react template
application okay so in this case we can
go ahead and cd into our app so cd slack
oops slack clone youtube okay i'm inside
right now
now what i want to do is go ahead and do
code insiders if you have the normal vs
code you just have to do code but i'm
going to do code insiders dot and that's
because i use the beta version okay so
that will go ahead and spin up a coding
environment for us right this is going
to be the easiest way to get up and
running with uh
[Laughter]
yeah you know how we do it i said it i
said it right let's go ahead and carry
on right so in this case slack clone
here we go this is what you want to do
guys right you'll get your starter
template over here now jumping into
source you'll see a few different
folders that you might not be used to if
you go ahead
and do the regular create react app the
new folders that you want to be
interested in as this one over here
we've got features with this random
counter folder we've got this over here
counter module and all this other stuff
right so i'm going to show you guys
break it down make it very simple but
before we do that i want to actually go
ahead and prep my firebase so i want to
go to
firebase.google.com and then what i want
to do is go to i love that one by gwen
he goes uh
uh he replied to your certificate
comment yeah guys honestly i don't know
why everyone's obsessed with
certificates get the work right get the
skill screw the certificate let's carry
on all right i'm telling you straight
papa we don't mess around in the pub fun
we just get jobs that's it period right
so in this case you want to click on go
to console
right once we've got this up and running
and we're just going to get into a
coding flow today it's going to be a
hell of a lot of fun we're just going to
get into this and we're just going to
run right so once your firebase console
is up and running
you want to go here and you want to make
sure you jump in and add a project okay
so here you want to do slack
oops slack clone
i'm going to say slack clone youtube all
right so mine's going to be for the
youtube and i'm going to go ahead and
click continue now i'm not going to
enable google analytics you can if you
want but i'm not gonna do it okay guaro
gerard says great to have you back thank
you dude really really appreciate the
support dash santosh welcome man dash
you killed it in the challenge in the
netflix challenge a five day challenge
if anyone hasn't done it checked out
make sure you do as a hell of a lot of
fun right zubie says is this live well i
answered your question dude let's jump
in
right so finishing up let's click on
continue at this point we should be
thrown into the firebase console where
we want okay this is perfect so now what
we want to do is click this little cog
icon okay click project settings right
let's go ahead guys and smash that
thumbs up button as well guys so smash
the thumbs up button because we had a
technical issue we already had like 250
likes or something before the video
started but this is a little bit of a
technical glitch so smash the like
button if you're watching it will help
this video get to as many people as
possible we have 183 people watching so
guys i should see 183 likes come on guys
let's keep on going what's up luke good
to see you man luke was uh an amazing
member of the netflix challenge hell of
a lot of fun and now he is inside zero
to full stack hero and he's officially
part of the papa fam welcome dude
right so you want to go down here click
on this web icon now over here i'm going
to type in slack clone youtube
set up firebase hosting boom register
the app
and let's carry on all right so
i can see uh twitch comments as well
guys what's up comp and code all right
so i'm gonna click next and then at this
point if you haven't installed this
you're gonna probably have to do this
and you'll most have most likely have to
do sudo npm install dash g so you make
sure you do that okay at this point i'm
gonna do that later so i'm gonna click
continue now i just want to say welcome
to everyone we've got 111 likes that's
what i'm talking about guys let's get it
to 200 let's get that number oh let's
get the energy up let's go all right
this is what i'm talking about man craig
williams bro thank you for this you
really are motivating developers dude
thank you for watching honestly okay
let's go down here let's go ahead and
hit the config now this is what we need
the firebase config over here right so
what i want to do is i'm going to copy
this now i'm going to jump over to my
code right so now obviously my code this
is not ideal i'm going to open up a
second desktop and you guys should get
familiar with setting up a flow like
this
okay so you want your flow to be very
efficient so this way i'm looking for my
firebase over here and i've got my code
editor over here perfect i don't need
the terminal anymore so i can close that
so at this point guys what i want to do
is i want to go to the source and before
we even do anything i'm going to add a
file called firebase.js
and remember that config over here that
we grabbed i'm just going to click copy
one more time jump here paste all right
so that's our starting point okay uh
prathan says i really like your linkedin
con thank you so much guys we're already
121 likes come on let's get energy up
man let's get this energy up i really
really love being back and uh yeah i'm
just pumped to be back okay because this
is gonna be a hell of a lot of fun this
one i actually got really excited
because styled components is in this
build so it's gonna be something new for
everyone who's watching on this channel
and uh and guys trust me when i say this
code is clean
it is clean this is like one of the
cleanest bits of code i've written so
let's jump into this all right go ahead
over to app.js and what i want to do is
i don't need the app.test.js file logo
svg and setup test so this will freeze
my computer because if my loyal
followers know i can't delete stuff and
without it dying so i'm going to move to
trash and we're just going to oh wow
it actually worked
people like going on papa fam will know
that that's been a struggle all right
let's carry on nice so what we're going
to do here is grab everything inside the
header and boom i'm going to type in h1
and let's say let's build slack let's
build slack boom and then i'm going to
go ahead and delete these two lines
right here we don't need the counter we
don't need the logo and i'm going to
change this to a lowercase a however
we're going to be using um we're not
using bem today we're using style
components so it's going to be a lot of
fun right a hell of a lot of fun now
what i want to do is command j right on
jay open up my terminal
and while everything's working we're
going to go ahead and click this
features over here now i want you guys
to pay
like very close attention to what i'm
about to do okay so inside of features
right we have counter slice now what i
want you to do is grab counter slice and
drag it on top of features because
what's actually happened is it's inside
of a folder called counter okay so i
want you to drag counter slice on top of
features click move
now you can see it's outside the counter
folder so at this point i want you to
right click on counter and click delete
right we don't want the counter folder
anymore okay perfect now we have counter
slice and this is all part of redux okay
so everything here is part of redux and
i really love nj dave's comment here he
says repetition is the best way to learn
and dude i completely agree with you
honestly i completely agree with you
repetition is the way to go right at
this point we're going to get an error
so i want to go into my app store.js and
here because we got rid of that counter
folder i need to go here and say
boom get rid of that so it's features
forward slash counter slice now we will
be renaming this in a bit but we'll come
back to redux in a second okay so
delete through the terminal says robert
hey i have actually done that before
it's actually quicker
says dad i can donate here paypal give
me your link oh [ __ ] thank you dude
there's a link to donate inside the
description um there's a tips and
donation link thank you so much dude
appreciate you all right let's carry on
guys so um we're going to go back to our
app.js and here inside the terminal i'm
going to go ahead and type in yarn start
because we're using yarn today because
that's what we do now right before we
used to use npm but you know i started
to enjoy the the yarn side of things
like some some people are looking at me
right now like with that with that evil
eye they're just like you know why why
don't you use npm but here's what it is
you know right so now we're going to
carry on i've already got an app running
on this port over here so i'm going to
click on yes we'll open it up on 3001.
and just while this loads guys i just
want to run you through the app one more
time okay so we have our amazing chat
functionality over here right so this is
a fully fledged slack phone right it
says fully fledged if we go into like a
chat over here i'm going to show you how
to deploy all this we have this
beautiful sidebar everything over here
you can see it pulls our name from and
our picture from google login really
really nice stuff and you can go ahead
and even add a channel let's go ahead
and say this was like let's just say the
papa chat right
okay and let's jump into the puppet chat
and let's go i said you see it says
message papa so if i go ahead and say yo
what's up
and look at that guys we get a nice
slack interface right so really really
slick okay and this is going to be using
style components it's so clean honestly
i really want you guys to look forward
to this now um
if i click this and there you see right
so you can go and sign up so i'm going
to sign in one more time so that we have
this as a reference and then i'm going
to be building a fresh app out of this
right so now i'm going to go over and
while this is loading give it one second
i'm just going to quickly log into that
account and then this will redirect in
just a sec i'm going to go ahead and
pull over the local host one so this is
our fresh app okay it says let's build
slack this is where you guys should be
at this point now i do want to mention
if you can't or you find it hard to kind
of code along with me then remember guys
the second link in the description
actually actually has the link to the
papa github repo which is actually on
sale as well right now we have 25 off
and you can pretty much go ahead grab it
and it's got the code for slack inside
of it as well as every single clone i've
ever done before make sure you go ahead
and check it out if you get stuck and
you know you can't keep up with
everything that's going on so uh it will
help you out in terms of sticking uh and
sticking up to speed with me okay so
let's carry on guys
uh please don't spam the chat dude so
i'm gonna go ahead and check you in
timeout so don't spam that and
everyone's asking about why i've left cp
uh guys this i don't need a reason i
just don't want to i want to kind of
carry on in my own route and i've built
i feel like i can deliver actual value
here in the way that i feel is most
efficient okay and plus we've got the
pup of fam guys like
get with it right let's carry on
let's go let's build a slack all right
so the first thing we want to do right
this is going to be a slightly different
tutorial right so the first thing we
want to do is we will be using react
router in today's build right so that
way we can have pagering inside of our
application so
a lot a lot of fun in today's build okay
and guys we're almost at 200 likes to
smash the likes let's get them up right
we were at 200 before it even started so
this is gonna be a fresh one the first
stream went down but we are not going to
let this one beat us okay so first thing
we're going to do is i'm going to go
ahead and install react to router so i'm
going to go over here and say react
router in google okay we're going to
wait till this loads out and then i'm
going to go to the react rear docks
right
and let's see
and let's click on declarative routing
for react.js
and this way a sag
there we go the stream's perfectly fine
at this point
jump over to twitch if you're having any
issues so at this point we can go ahead
and we're going to copy this we need to
install reactor or dom okay so i'm going
to copy this go back to my app and i
like to have a split terminal
so a lot of people don't like to have
sort of split there the second one i
like to have a split terminal because
then i can see both things at once but
what i do is i make this one smaller
okay so that way i can see everything
here i'll say yarn add and i'll do react
with dom boom okay
mohammed says i love you sonny you're
just amazing thank you dude what's up
assad good to see you man
right so we're installing reactor dom so
now we have reactor inside our app the
easiest way to get this up and running
go ahead copy the import statements
let's go ahead and pop this in right
here
boom copy and let's go ahead and paste
it over here and then what i'm going to
do is i'm going to grab everything
inside of router
there we go and then this jump over here
right so
a towel says hey sonny can we use react
hooks over redux of course you can let's
go ahead and paste it inside of here
right and i'm going to get rid of my h1
over here so at this point if we save
our application you should be able to
see what i see at this point right so
we've got a router and what we want to
do is everything inside the nav we don't
want that okay i don't really care about
all that stuff right now we don't care
about that right then the thing that i
need next is i'm going to change this
div
into an actual just a fragment okay
because i actually don't need that div
at this point i'm going to get rid of
this comment
now what is a react router okay so react
router allows us to have different pages
on our website so if we go to forward
slash it will take us to this home
component if we go to four slash users
it will take us to the user's component
and if we go to forward slash about will
take us to the about component now we
don't have these pages so for now i'm
gonna go ahead and get rid of them okay
so at this point i'm gonna go ahead and
do this uh harsh please don't spam dude
i will be sending out right so i'm gonna
go ahead and say h1 and let's just say
this is the home page and just to make
it extremely clear now when we're on the
home page what will happen is i'm going
to make it firstly an exact
route which means you have to land on
the home page only and now if we go back
to our application let's go ahead and
check it out it says this is the home
page okay perfect stuff works just as we
expected it so now we have a react
router set up your garage said i
recently got an integer internship
because of you your youtube channel
streams thanks dude and great job you
did that dude that's amazing i'd love to
have you inside the papa fam so check it
out zero to full stack hero first link
in description do jump in with us please
i love having success stories inside of
it and we have we literally had gwen and
alex who just landed jobs as well so
crazy stuff let's carry on guys all
right
so christopher says hey sunny thanks for
the quality lessons with you i hope i
was able to get a job with a fortune 500
company let's go man that's sick well
done dude that is so sick
dude that is incredible stuff right so
now we've got the homepage here so what
we need to do now app.css clear
everything we don't want anything go to
index.css and at the top i want to do
the following i want to say target
everything with a margin of zero
and what i'm going to do is you guys
love when i do this i'm going to go
ahead and pop this on one side and pop
the co the actual application on the
other side so let's go ahead and pop
this over here
perfect so now you guys can see i've got
if i go ahead and add this
margin of zero you guys should be able
to see let me go ahead and get rid of
that you see this little imaginary gap
over here right this is going to go
ahead and disappear when we add a margin
of zero so if i go ahead and save you
can see boom it gets rid of the
imaginary gap okay so that's the first
step that we wanted to do the second
step i actually want to do is i'm going
to set something in body today right i'm
going to set a css variable now css
variable is a very similar to a
javascript variable pretty much it just
holds the value okay so what we're going
to do is i'm going to have a slack color
right css variable and this is how we
define it right we pretty much just say
slack color and then we do this we just
give it the color and now we can go
ahead and access the slack color like so
okay and then what i'm going to do is
i'm going to go ahead and say overflow
hidden that way in case we have any
overflow inside of our app we're going
to hide it okay so i'm just going to
protect myself later on so now boom get
rid of that and then get rid of that now
we're back inside of app.js so firstly
i'm going to mark out the application
okay so let's look at the final
application and see what we got to do so
we have a few things in this build right
we have the header so we have this
beautiful header over here okay we have
a nice looking header we have a sidebar
over here we have a chat input component
we have the chat itself over here and we
also have the login stuff right so if i
want to go ahead go ahead and go back
here we have the login page
so
what i might do first is actually build
maybe the uh
let's build let's start building the app
first it's always funny to start
building the actual application first so
i'm going to go ahead and start doing
that one first i encourage many friends
of mine to watch your videos hashtag
popperfum that's what we're talking
about guys amazing stuff
all right ataro says bro just do one
session on react hooks dude i cover all
of that inside the zero to full stack
hero first nation dude best community on
the planet i said it because it's true
period let's carry on all right so this
is the home page okay and uh you know
you're good when you start getting
people
a couple your builds you know it's
pretty fun pretty fun when you get that
all right so i'm going to go ahead and
save there we go and then here you can
see
i have um
hey nice fin
okay let's carry on so we've got the
home page over here right so what i'm
going to do now is for the home page
i'm going to go ahead and actually
firstly let's go ahead and do the
the header component okay so i'm going
to go ahead and set up a header
component so over here i'm gonna go
ahead and say okay the header will go
here the header like so right so what i
need to do is obviously create a header
component so i'm gonna say header
dot js now i'm using snippets okay so
i'm using rfce allows me to create a
functional component how did i do that
in case you're new to the channel go to
extensions and you want to make sure you
get this extension right here es7 react
redux graphql react native snippets they
are incredible okay really really
incredible stuff and uh yeah just make
sure you you download this look 2
million 2 million 2.3 2.4 million wow
crazy stuff right let's carry on so at
this point we've got the header okay so
let's jump into the header and see what
we need so the first thing i'm going to
need inside the header is let's have a
look at it we have a header left section
so i'm going to assume that this is my
header left section and then i have a
header middle with this fancy input and
then i have a header right with just
this little icon over here now how do i
get these icons right i need something
called material ui right so i'm going to
go ahead and jump into that right now
i'm going to go ahead and go over to
materialui.com and i'm going to install
this into my project so the first thing
i want to do is it says npm install
material ui now if i'm using yarn i
simply copy i jump over command j and i
do yarn add
material ui call okay so that will work
perfectly for me at this point what i
can do what's that print up i can go
here and say icons because what you need
to do is you need to in
install the core as well as the icons
that come with material ui so i'm going
to go ahead and copy that as well and
then once it's done i'm going to say
yarn add material ui icons boom perfect
right mr zac says what's the subject
today what are we building right we're
going to be building the slack clone
right but it's a redox styled components
jacked up version incredible stuff right
um
there is a link in the description dude
you can go ahead and check it out it's
at the bottom thank you so much dude
right so at this point what we're gonna
do we're gonna go ahead and say
uh we've already done this now to search
for those icons i'd simply go to this
link here where it says you can search
for the full list of these icons i click
that okay and then here you can see i've
got a search right so if i go ahead and
type in send for example it'll give me a
send icon and they'll give me the import
statement for it this is how i go ahead
and do that right this is how i find all
the icons that we're going to need
throughout the builds okay now guys
we're almost at 200 likes smash that
thumbs up button to help this video get
out to as many people as possible it's
going to be a hell of a lot of fun today
guys let's carry on right we would have
been a 400 if that's stupid internet
right but it's fine we're all good we're
stronger than this i think we can keep
pushing i really think we can keep going
right
so at this point i'm gonna go ahead and
say
um close this because we've already got
that right so we have the header now i'm
gonna be using styled components now
what are styled components okay styled
components are simply put we're not
going to be using css in this in the
traditional way where we import a css
file and then we kind of you know we
style out some stuff and we use the bem
naming convention typically where a div
has a class name and then we sort of
target the class name but today we're
changing things right we're changing it
up we're going to be using something
called start components now i want to
show you what style components are all
about why they're so popular okay so
start components they have pretty much
the power behind um
they're pretty much more powerful than
css modules they do a lot of head like
uh of heavy lifting for you behind the
scenes and they make your app extremely
fast now if you're wondering who uses it
just check out this list right tons of
places use this thing right so all these
folks use it vimeo vogue
uh
the onion i don't know what that is but
uh eurostar coinbase
get that dodge coin guys get right and
this is pretty much how we define it you
pretty much use define a variable so
imagine we wanted to find a button and
then you pretty much say style dot and
then you give this sort of if it was a
div here i'd say div and then you pretty
much give some css inside of it now
trust me it's not as tricky as you think
okay it's really not that tricky i'm
going to show you guys how to do it all
so we're going to click documentation
and we're going to click installation
over here okay so
uh it says npm install and then start
components and guys this is the papa fam
video okay so
like if you want to be a part of the pub
farm community first link in the
description make sure you check it out
we're already 200 strong inside the
community it's crazy so i'm going to go
ahead and grab start components here i'm
going to say yarn add styled components
boom okay
um perfect
gwen says i love the fact that we can
actually pause the video
and i'm gonna go to the bottom okay so
to make sure i'm at the bottom i go to
the second last tag comma and i'm gonna
go ahead and paste so you see resolution
styled components right so it's very
simple thing you just need to copy what
i just did there okay 200 likes that's
what i'm talking about guys see we had
issues with the internet we didn't let
that stop us papa fam is way stronger
than that i love you guys thank you so
much honestly just keep on going all
right i'm going to hit save on that and
it's still installing styled components
so we can give that just to sex and uh
be patient with that one right and you
can see pretty much after that we can
just use them okay so we're going to use
that firstly inside of the uh inside of
our header component and trust me guys
it will make a lot of sense when we jump
into this and when we start running with
it okay so we're gonna pretty much just
okay we're gonna get get ready for this
okay
um so let's carry on guys
and uh what we're gonna do now is
all right
so please don't spam dude i hate it when
people spam like i'm actually gonna
block people from this channel if you
spam so ayushman dude you're out right
let's go so um
what we're gonna it was installing the
style components that's why i was kind
of freaking out so at this point we have
style components installed okay so what
we're gonna do is is we're gonna go here
and even this one dude wow so many
people are spamming dude so any
moderator so pranav do you mind just
sort of you know you can time out people
i'll give you permission go ahead and
just clean up that chat right so over
here what we're gonna do is i'm gonna go
ahead and rather than having divs right
this is how we use styled components
okay so i'm going to make this a little
bit bigger for you guys i think that
might be easier for you to see so how do
we go ahead and use a testing is we
don't have a css file which is really
nice in that sense okay we get rid of
the css file now what we do is it
actually lives underneath oh which is
really nice in that sense okay that's
the sort of standard that we should be
doing okay so it should live underneath
the uh the stream over there so at this
point
what we're gonna do is we're gonna go
ahead and say
let's go ahead and have a header
container okay so i'm going to say const
header container like this okay equals
styled right because it's styled
components which we have to import oh no
it's not that one oops not that
definitely not that one right what we're
going to do instead we're going to
import it and we're going to go ahead
and say import styled from styled
components like this we say style.div
okay now here what we need to do is go
ahead and do backticks so these are not
regular ticks guys okay so they're back
ticks okay you do back ticks and then
what you want to do is start styling it
okay so let's just say imagine the color
of the text here was red okay so we said
color let's just say red
okay so these are back ticks etc let's
go ahead and do that
and then oops i need to go ahead mine
has like nice syntax highlighting okay
and you might be wondering but sunny
mine looks a bit like this right
everything is this color now what you
need to do
okay is you need to go ahead and guys if
anyone's having issues with the internet
pretty much just go ahead and uh refresh
your browser and it should be all good
to go now okay so we should be fine you
just need to do a refresh and it's all
good okay
so at this point what we're gonna do is
we're gonna go ahead and i'm just gonna
play my music instead of doing the uh
the other one okay there we go so at
this point what we're gonna do is go
ahead and jump over to
your extensions okay so over here in the
extensions panel i'm going to go ahead
into extensions and you want to grab
this over here okay so grab the where is
it gone you want to make sure you get vs
code styled component extension and what
this does is it gives you color
syntax highlighting for your styled
components without it it's going to be a
bit of a headache okay and uh guys if
anyone asks why i'm not with cp anymore
i'm just going to block you honestly
it's really annoying uh guys i'm i
deliver more value over here period and
we've got you know chill out all right
let's carry on
right so i'm going to go ahead and get
rid of this one the stream has not ended
you can just refresh dude all right so
at this point where we have the header
okay so what i'm going to do is i'm
going to say header
container
okay
and now you can see what's happened is
this is simply got these styles injected
into it so now if i have a h1 which says
test
okay and i go into my app.js and i
import the header
like so
and i save i'm going to go ahead and pop
this to the side and let's go ahead and
go back over here okay now
inside of here you can see what the
really cool thing about this right is if
i go ahead and say background color
let's do background color red and then
i'm going to go ahead and refresh let me
see my header container is a style div
there we go the background color is red
um interesting okay let's double check
what's going on here but what we want to
do is let's just start jumping into
actually the coding aspect of it oh
there we go that's why
um
okay i know why so at this point imagine
i want to target that h1 what i need to
do is i just go ahead and say okay
target the h1 inside of here and give it
a color of red so let's go ahead and do
color of red
like this save
right and this will go ahead and uh this
will actually this will do it right it's
actually i'm not sure why it's not
rendering let's double check what's
happening over here
right
so what i would recommend is if you do
experience any of these issues ctrl c
and then you're gonna do yarn start
again okay the reason why this is
happening is because we've installed
style components we need to make sure
that we go ahead and restart our
terminal i'm gonna do y 3001
and then we'll wait for this to start up
again
okay
right and i'm gonna go ahead and refresh
save
perfect now style div okay i'm gonna say
color let's just say green
and then let's go ahead and pop it in
perfect
and
now
we'll go ahead and we'll fix this in a
sec okay i'm not sure exactly what i've
done here but uh let's go ahead and
carry on i'm gonna carry on with the
build and then we'll fix this okay so we
have the header container right now the
header container is gonna have a bunch
of style inside of it but as we
mentioned before we have a header left
section okay so inside of here i'm gonna
have a header left so let's go ahead and
say like a header left
uh we're gonna have a header right and
i'm gonna show you guys what i'm
referring to here so imagine our local
host 3000 so this is our actual slack
app i'll show you how to do that cool
stuff as well we'll say header middle or
sort of header search we'll call the
middle one
all right head to search and then we'll
have header right okay
header right
right
now
is green not green
oh okay really oh wait a sec no that
shouldn't be the reason right color
green
oh dude you're right yeah you're
actually right let's go ahead and do
that boom
there we go and it will actually pop in
now so if we go into h1
just
save there we go that's correct yeah
you're right my bad nice shout out
daniel good [ __ ] all right so let's go
ahead and carry on so there you go you
see it applies the style to that div
okay so we have three sections over here
so what are we referring to at this
point header left is going to be the
left section we've got the middle
section which is going to be the search
and then we've got the right section
over here so let's go ahead and jump
through okay so
header left
first thing we're going to do is create
a constant we're going to say header
left so i'm going to go and say const
header left like so equals a star div
right and remember you if you want a h1
or h2 you can just say style dot h2 and
it works in that way as well right so uh
that's actually really cool uh are you
schmann dude you continue to spam so
dude like i'm hiding you from the
channel now i've i warned once and then
it just continued to continue spam dude
so you're out all right so let's go
ahead and carry out we've got the header
left so we're gonna go ahead and create
a header left section over here and this
is actually very clean guys because if
think about it this way your css is
never going to go ahead and overlap okay
it's never going to overlap which is
amazing if you do it this way whereas
css by itself can easily overlap so you
have to be careful with that okay now we
do we are going to use an avatar here so
this top left section over here is an
avatar right so this is actually derived
from material ui so what i'm going to do
is i'm going to import this over here so
i'm going to say import avatar from
material ui core like so and then what
i'm going to do is i'm going to go in
here and actually rather than directly
using the uh material ui avatar i'm
going to make it a start component i'm
kind of getting sick of that music so i
want my music back on epidemic boom
there we go we're going to have our
tunes back
there we go it's going to be a lot of
fun now this helps me get into a jam you
know that kind of you know a jam state
psycho coda what's up dude
welcome to the stream man smash the
thumbs up button if you're here and
you're enjoying it it's gonna be a lot
of fun today so buckle up and we're
gonna get into a nice flow at this point
okay so
header left let's go ahead and build out
this left section right so to have a
styled avatar right how do we do that so
over here i'm going to say const and
let's go ahead and say header avatar
okay and you can actually name these
whatever you want there is no real
standard at this point you can define it
but what if it's not a default sort of
like div or h1 or if it's actually like
a custom component right so what i'm
going to do here is i'm going to grab
the avatar and what i do is i do
parentheses avatar right that's how you
do it and then i have the double
quotes right and then you can make your
own styled component out of it which is
actually incredibly simple okay so
really really easy now random rabbit
studio says i actually like putting my
style components in its own file good
spot so you can right you very easily
can move your styled components out of
the code base and into their own files
in this tutorial i'm going to be
building inside of the same file and
we're going to be doing that way but i
will be introducing a folder structure
in this build so good thing you reminded
me dude i'm going to go ahead and say
components
right and inside the components folder
i'm going to grab my header and i'm
going to drag it inside now and all of
our components except the high level one
like app.js and i'm going to update the
imports yes
let's go ahead and go and save our input
import sorry so inside of app.js and now
it says components header save
make sure when you do that it all works
okay i'm gonna
refresh
and let's go ahead and see if we made
any mistake okay so it should be all
good now at this point and it's
compiling there we go okay so at this
point the header left right so header
avatar sorry inside of header left what
i'm going to do is i have a header
avatar i'm going to go ahead and pop
that in here so i'm going to say header
avatar
right header avatar and then i'm going
to go ahead and it's a self-closing
bracket okay so what we're going to do
at this point is
oh dude i really am getting irritated
with these like with these spammy
comments dude i see it but if you
continue to like send messages i'm just
going to block you okay so at this point
um
on click i'm going to have a long click
for this one this is going to be the
sign out but we're going to do that
afterwards i'm going to say to do
and that's a special extension that i'm
using there i'm going to say add on
click right so we're going to come back
to that one and then we're going to say
the alternative and the source now the
source here would actually be something
like the user's picture okay so this is
going to be the user's picture as we see
here but we're going to go ahead and
leave it blank for now okay so it's
gonna be a blank image for now and then
what i'm gonna do is i'm actually gonna
have the time icon so the time icon is
this one over here
okay so let's carry on
let's go ahead and jump over here
so
i'm gonna go ahead and save at this
point and let's see if we see it there
we go guys look our first little import
perfect okay um and pranav don't go
ahead and uh you know don't worry just
don't acknowledge people who spam that's
fine um so at this point we're going to
go ahead and leave the header avatar now
this the next thing i'm going to do is
pop in a icon okay so from material ui
so here i'm going to say import
access time icon i'm going to go
underneath here pop it in there like so
now we have our time icon as well we
should just jump in in a second there we
go guys okay so we have the little icon
and i'm going to make this eventually
look like this okay so stay tuned and
you'll find out how
so header left the first thing i want to
do is i want to give my a container some
styles so how do we do it when we're
using styled components it's pretty
simple actually we pretty much go here
and we just assume that this is regular
css inside of this we say display flex
and we do our regular sort of things
right so we say display flex and this
takes normal css rules so at this point
we don't see much changing okay so i'm
going to go ahead and firstly jump into
my header left styles okay so here i'm
going to say header left div and inside
of here what i'm going to do is i'm
going to go ahead and pop in the
following styles so we said display
flex in here and i want this one to take
up a third of the overall screen so i'm
going to say effects 0.3 okay then i
want this also to be a type display flex
i'm going to align the items centrally
so i'm going to go ahead and say align
item centrally and i'm going to give it
a margin left of 20 pixels because i
don't want it to touch rich programmer
what's up dude frank in the house
awesome slack 2.0 build let's go man
thank you so much frank for that clutch
donation appreciate you dude
all right
stormbreaker um redux template is
actually extremely easy and if you want
to find the easiest thing to use it's
recoil
we cover it inside the course but yeah
recoil is the easiest thing to use guys
right so the backticks are for the
syntax yes because we actually have some
kind of in uh props interpolation some
at some points okay now to target this
right target this icon so material ui
icons by default get the special class
and it's called material ui svg icon
dash root okay so at this point what i'm
going to do is if there is ever an icon
inside of here right inside the header
left so in this case access time icon
i'm going to target the icon by doing
this and this means inside header left
i'm going to target the material ui svg
root icon and i'm going to apply a style
so here what i'm going to do it's going
to say margin left auto and margin right
30 pixels save it and at this point you
can see we're starting to get this
spacing
correct
nice
okay and the reason why this is good is
because we're doing a flex roll so this
entire sort of top is flex and then
we're saying 0.3 flex so it's only
taking up
30 at this point right so this is 30
okay so i shouldn't save that but this
is actually 30 at this point right my
arrows are a bit dodgy
okay
so we have a 30 looking you know left
side over there which is pretty good so
let's go ahead and carry on so you guys
can already see it's pretty nice
actually to be fair right it's actually
pretty nice now what if i want to target
that header avatar right so i'm going to
go over to the header avatar and i want
to make it so that it actually looks
like it's a clickable element so firstly
i'm going to say okay grab it and say
cursor pointer
right and then what i'm going to say is
when i hover over it so you see how we
can apply the styles here it's actually
quite a nice syntax right when i hover
over i'm going to say the opacity
should change to 0.8
okay so when i do this
now check this out guys when i hover
over this
can you see that right that's quite a
nice little effect that we have going on
over there
right finn heart says does zero to full
stack hero also talk about how to get
clients yes dude we actually talk about
that a lot we see zero to full stack
hero is not just about building and
constantly coding it's about how you go
ahead and take those skills and actually
land jobs and freelancing clients a lot
of coaching calls we talk about people
who just had interviews my tips and
tricks on how they can approach
interviews and every week it's amazing
because we can go ahead and have a chat
with our with our own sort of you know
students inside the course and we can
see how their progression goes now
what's amazing about that guys and i
will carry on in just a sec is that
people have got jobs and then we have
feedback sessions in the coaching course
so really honestly you won't find that
anywhere else so it's it's for the
community that's why we've done it right
uh emerson says it's about the community
best ever exactly dude it's all about
the community that's exactly what we
strive for inside right
so for the header container i'm going to
go ahead and say position fixed and i'll
show you what i'm doing it's a little
bit of a hack what i'm doing here but
i'm saying position is fixed i want to
say a width of 100
and uh this will make a lot of sense
later and i'm going to say align the
item centrally and this will come into
play in just a sec afterwards line item
center
and then i'm going to go ahead and say
justify the content space between give
it a bit of padding so let's go ahead
and pop that in
save and you can see it should have a
little bit of padding at the top now and
then i'm going to say the background
color remember that css variable that we
defined earlier right it has to access
it all you need to do is type in
var
slack color right and remember where we
defined this was inside of
index.css over here remember slack color
we defined the variable here the css
variable and here we're using it okay
and we're making the color of the text
white there we go and that's because
these are actually sort of simple bits
of text pretty much
okay um i use something called screen
brush for the the sort of writing on the
screen what's up morocco's in the house
hey guys we're almost at 300 300 likes
let's keep going guys let's keep on
going all right so this is looking
pretty good right this is looking pretty
good at this point now let's go ahead
and fix the header search okay so the
header search section next priyanshu
what's up man good to see you here dude
hey
header search is the next bit okay so
over here i'm gonna say okay let's
create a header search start component
perfect right and inside the header
search we're going to have the search
icon so the search icon is actually from
material ui so i need to go ahead and
import that and you're probably
wondering but sunny you just wrote a
header search but you never defined it
right what is that about and you're
right i need to go ahead and define that
so i'll go down to the bottom and i'm
going to just add it to the top so that
way you guys can see
i'm going to say const header search and
this is going to be a style div and you
can see look it's not really not that
difficult to start getting the hang of
it okay so you can go style div and now
we can access the styles for it very
very simple stuff okay
um
so perfect stuff now we're gonna use
print up i'm not gonna use that today
but i might use the
app bar for material ui in a future
build that's a very good call dude um so
at this point i'm going to say header
search there we go
and i'm going to go ahead and check
we've already got the search icon over
there so i'm going to save okay
and then let's go ahead and you can see
at this point we've got some kind of
search icon being pushed over to the
right and that makes sense okay and i'll
tell you why in a sec so we've got the
search icon over here i'm going to have
an input field
now this input field is going to
hopefully make kicks in there we go it's
going to be of type text by default it's
already type text so we can get rid of
that we're going to say the placeholder
in this case is going to be to search
the proper firm all right because this
is going to be like the uh
sort of the slack for the papa farm
right and also just to mention guys if
you didn't already know we have an
incredible slack community inside zero
tool stack hero first link in the
description check it out sale runs out
in two days guys then i'm closing the
doors to the community so i want to miss
out on it honestly second link is
actually all of the code as well so you
know we're going crazy with sales right
now right so at the top of this screen
we have the search the puffer fan right
now i want that to look like this and be
in the correct position so how do i get
it to that point all right i'm going to
go over to my header search and what's
really cool is if i command click it
will actually sort of open up the header
search in the styled component location
so at this point we have that over here
right and then i'm going to go ahead and
apply a bunch of styles so
this bit took up 0.3 so 30 in the screen
i want the middle bit to take up 40 of
the screen okay so uh ever since
incredible no it's outstanding that's it
jamie davis yo yo what's up man
good to see you here i'm going to say
flex 0.4 right and guys if you just
noticed how quick we're going like it's
insane right we get more views and likes
than channels with hundreds of thousand
subscribers like
i think that's incredible i think we
should be proud of that as a family man
i think the whole papa fam should be
proud of that as a team this is not just
me this is built from you guys and this
is what we're about okay so like let's
go ahead and give ourselves like a huge
pat on the back for that because
honestly the way we're growing the way
what is happening it's so damn powerful
man
so i'm gonna go ahead and give this a
border color this is a slight gray color
and say text align center and you can
start to see guys look there's a slight
background being uh being chucked in
jamie davis that's a testament to the
value you provide us thank you so much
dude really really appreciate that
display flex padding not 50. i'm going
to go ahead and check that in here
save and you can see it starts to line
up okay it's starting to line up and
then we're going to say color of gray
and a border i'm going to go ahead and
chuck in the border and the color gray
over here now
at this point okay yeah it's looking
okay but i need to target that input
field right so the thing i love about
start components is we're already inside
of header search and inside of header
search is an input field which means
that we can go ahead and target the
input just like that which is a lot
simpler right fantana says oh we are
amazing for sure thanks to you sonny
appreciate it so much honestly really
really appreciate the cameras thank you
at this point i'm gonna say the
background color of this one is gonna be
transparent okay so background color
transparent i'm gonna go ahead and get
the energy up right now guys because
we're about to break 300 likes i think
we should step it up a bit let's go guys
all right
transparent there we go and at this
point i'm gonna go ahead and say border
none
and text align let's change the color up
in here as well right text align center
and i'm going to give it a minimum width
right
min width and i'm going to give this min
width to 30 view width
save
and at this point you can see look at
that it perfectly places itself in the
way that we expected okay now at this
point this looks pretty good but you see
we get this that kind of outline now the
quick fix to the outline is you simply
go ahead and do outline
zero or none pretty much i think zero
would work yeah there you go zero works
nicely and you see the color of the text
right we're gonna change that as well
i'm just gonna make the color of the
text to white
there we go save boom
all right sunny yeah exactly yeah
and there we go okay so at this point
what we're going to do is we have the
middle section complete now the reason
why it's not being pushed out like this
is because we don't have our right
section complete so i'm going to go
ahead and create the right section over
this point right so christopher asked he
says is
uh is zero to full stack hero platinum
only for a period of time or will it
include any future courses so
christopher just to let you know the
offer right now is currently a huge sale
we have right now so first link in the
description if anyone wants to know
about that but if you join now as part
of this sale it includes access to all
the courses available right now as well
as all of the ones listed on the site
and that's not going to be the case
after the sale okay we're going to
change it after the sale and the price
is going to go up as well and that's so
that we can enable the community to stay
with the quality high quality
individuals who want to be invested and
kind of want to grow so that's my treat
to you guys for hitting 2021k if you
didn't see my instagram post 20k
instagram 21k youtube now we're at 22.
crazy stuff right but yes it includes
all access to all content packs platinum
is lifetime diamond is lifetime silver
and gold are monthly memberships okay so
there you go dude
let's carry on so the next thing concept
is very cool dude i agree with you right
so um let's carry on guys so here we
have this let's go ahead and create the
header right okay
so header right over here now what we're
going to do is we're going to say right
like we go oh nice we just got a
donation
from
uncle gatsby 3.99 he says hi sunny do
you have any experience with gaspi if so
do you have any tutorials on it thank
you so much for what you do for us dude
i love that thank you so much to answer
your question we do we are going to be
covering gatsby inside the course uh but
we will be covering it okay so just
something to be aware of um but in the
future hell yeah dude you know me i'm
gonna cover all that stuff all right
header right okay so at this point
header right what i'm gonna do is i'm
gonna go ahead and create header right
so you wanna go down to the bottom
right
so i'm gonna go down to the bottom over
here and say const header like this
header or right oops and there we go now
remember if you oh nice we actually just
got sebastian just joined the papa fam
dude uh oh no so here sorry sebastian
donated my bad uh we've got someone else
joined the pop up just a second ago a
bit confusing about two messages uh
there we go let's carry on guys so
header right okay so we've got header
right over here
and then inside of header right what i'm
gonna have is the simply the help
outline icon okay so it's a simple icon
on the right hand side so at this point
and i love man i love this song i miss
coming live honestly let's go help
outline
this is how you have to cheer yourself
up when the sort of tech issues get in
the way
let's carry on
i mean i don't know anywhere else it has
this kind of vibe when you code honestly
like i love it and this is what i thrive
on this is what i try and do let's go
ahead and get rid of these comments
like if you're not having fun when
you're coding what are you doing
honestly
it should be a fun experience right like
is it obviously it gets it gets painful
i'm not gonna lie all right it gets
painful
right
faizan we have react basics and web dev
essentials being released nice i
recommend anyone to join platinum
platinum is my recommendation for anyone
to jump in we have the cell ending in
two days platinum is the one platinum is
lifetime dude like don't waste your
money on this membership the monthly
ones just do platinum get lifetime and
you're done
and then you'll be part of the community
for everything right which is crazy
muhammad says sending your vibe is
unstoppable that's what i'm talking
about guys right the music is actually
part of my epidemic sounds playlist so
i'm going to go ahead and fix this one
the bible says looking fresh thank you
dude all right now let's go ahead and
finish off styling the header right
let's go ahead and do that so over here
header right perfect jump down here to
style head around we're going to say the
final bit should be a flex 0.3 because
think about it guys this was 0.3 which
is 30
this is 0.4 which is 40
and i want the final one to be 0.3 that
means it'll be perfectly sort of
positioned around right vocal the first
link in the description to go ahead and
check it all out we're going to say flex
0.3
there we go and i'm going to go ahead
and say display flex
there we go let's save and now you can
see look at that guys looks really
really clean right now okay and i'm
going to actually align the items flex
end so that way it sticks to the right
and if you ever get tempted to go ahead
and do something like float
i will personally come to you and slap
you
so don't use hello anymore guys it's old
it's it's gone don't do it all right
don't do that stuff
let's carry on alright so at this point
i'm going to go ahead and i'm going to
target the material you uh the material
ui icon okay so at this point i'm going
to say a material eye icon
like this and inside of here i'm going
to do margin left of auto margin right
20 pixels
right
there we go sanjay loved that one
so guys look at that that looks pretty
fresh right look at that boom i don't
even see a difference man look at that
no flicker except the little icon we
will fix that okay so flexbox is clean
like if you learn how to use flexbox
you're gonna kill it four likes away
from 300 likes let's smash that like
button and go forward guys let's keep on
going strong
right so at this point what i'm going to
do is let's go ahead and build the
sidebar perhaps right so i think we're
done with that yep we're done with that
and guys look this is just an example of
how powerful uh styled components is
like look how clean this is boom look at
that and the css is just down here and
you can move this into a separate
component if you want i would recommend
saying header.style.js
if you're going to do it okay that'll be
my recommendation we have 305 likes
thank you so much guys just keep on
going i love it it's bring me back to
life after that little tech issue let's
just kill it guys let's kill it all
right so
next thing i want to do is that sidebar
right so i'm going to jump back over to
app.js and you're going to see that we
actually have a very clean build today
okay so the next part right the entire
app what i'm going to assume is that
this bit over here so all of this is
actually going to be something like an
app body okay so this whole thing is
going to be like the app body right and
then the header is always going to show
right that's how we're going to kind of
build this out all right so at this
point what i want to do
is i'm going to have the header over
here and what i'm going to do is i'm
actually going to take the header
outside the switch
right so the header should always be
present here and then what i'm going to
do is i'm going to have app body
right and app body is going to have
everything inside and it's all going to
be determined by a switch okay now at
this point um what we're going to do is
i'm going to actually change this build
up a little bit so we might actually not
need to over complicate this but
eventually what we're going to have is a
chat
inside of here this is going to be a
chat component okay and we will make it
look super clean super nice now app body
what is that right so we need to go
ahead and define it so here i'm going to
say constant outbody equals a styled div
all right star div and then we go back
ticks
and then what is this
float that you talk about so if you
don't know what float is then just just
don't worry about it just pretend you
didn't hear anything
all right so says forget it exists
you shouldn't be using flow anymore it's
just it's an old way of handling things
okay so i'm going to go to the top
and i'm going to go ahead and do boom
import start from start component save
right and go ahead and refresh there we
go okay so we have the app body now what
i can do with this app body is i can
start defining styles of everything that
goes underneath there okay so inside of
there all i'm going to have is actually
before we go ahead and finish that bit
i'm going to have something called a
sidebar okay so over here i'm actually
going to have a sidebar component so
here i'll say oops i'm going to say
sidebar
and this will be responsible for this
sidebar that you see right here okay so
that's going to be the sidebar over
there now at this point what i'm going
to do
is um
right uh my name's sunny dude vibe uh
all right so let's carry on so i'm going
to go ahead and create a sidebar
component so i'm going to go ahead and
pop it in here so i'm going to create
i'm going to go into my components
folder
create sidebar.js
okay and i'm going to say rfce right for
a react functional component with an
export right now over inside the sidebar
let's go ahead and start coding this up
all right so the first thing i want to
do is create a sidebar container so this
one i'm going to change it to a sidebar
container now over here i'm going to say
consider by container equals a style div
all right so it's going to be our
surrounding container outside the
application go ahead and pop that down
like so now at this point i need to make
sure i ins import react start components
like this okay now guys we are going to
break 400 likes i'm telling you this
keep on pushing this energy i love it i
really can't believe it like how small
are sort of not even small guys 22 000
followers like subscribers right now but
we just continue to break like what is
expected from a channel with 22k subs
right let's keep on getting those likes
up and let's just kill it let's just
keep on going man let's just show the
whole world we're about this is crazy
all right
sidebar container over here right now
the sidebar has a few areas it has a
header and then it has a few extra bits
down here these are all called sidebar
option components and we're going to go
ahead and build them out okay so i'm
going to go ahead and show you how to do
that uh today now the sidebar header
right so let's go ahead and focus on
this header section over here okay so
um what we're going to do now is create
a sidebar header so i'm going to go
ahead and say okay sidebar header
and then i need to create that so i'm
going to say
sidebar header equals a star div
start div there we go and save right so
now we have our sidebar header over here
now inside what goes inside the sidebar
header so i actually have two sections
here i have a left section which i'm
going to refer to as sidebar info okay
and then i have i'm going to inside of
here i'm going to have a h2 and a h3
okay so over here what i'm going to do
is create another one called sidebar
info i'm going to say sidebar info like
so
and i'm going to go ahead and create
this then a quick way of doing this is
boom and then you can go ahead and
rename this one to sidebar info like so
okay now inside of here i'm going to
have a h2 which says uh pop-up from hq
okay so this is going to refer to this
bit over here now underneath that i'm
gonna have a h3 and inside the h3 i'm
gonna firstly have this little drawing
icon right and this is actually got a
weird name to it right it's called fiber
manual record icon now god knows why
it's called that but it is what it is
okay
so it is what it is right and we're
literally climbing on those likes guys
let's keep it coming for fiber manual
icon so i'm gonna go ahead and import
that from material ui like so perfect
now underneath right i'm gonna go ahead
and have oh
dude i think we just got chris oh
welcome chris
just joined the uh papa platinum dude
dude welcome man welcome to the puppy
fun guys
we've got loads of members in the barber
room right now welcome christopher he
just jumped in the sale is the first
link in the description guys he joined
he made the right decision papa platinum
welcome dude
that's amazing
right so now we have the h3 over here
dude that just made me pumped up man and
then we're gonna have the user's name so
in this case what i'm gonna say is i'm
just gonna say sunny sanger for now and
then when we log in i'm actually gonna
pull that record from it okay jacob says
sonny you are my hero dude you are my
hero for watching so thank you so much
man all right now i'm going to go ahead
and import the sidebar into our app.js
so over here i'm going to say app.js and
i'm going to go ahead and import this
right
boom import save right i'm gonna go
ahead fontana that's fire dude the hell
yeah man
right the fam grows man cesar you're
right that's it dude we just keep on
growing man all right so at this point
how do we go ahead and get this to look
the way we need it so we have the
sidebar over here okay
and what i want to just double check is
that
okay so firstly app body let's go ahead
and style this in a way that we need to
okay
so i'm gonna go ahead and first when we
have the sidebar body i'm gonna say this
is display flex and it has a height of
100 view height okay because i want to
use up the entire height save like so
i'm going to refresh and you can still
you can't see anything right now okay
i'm going to fix that in just a second i
think that might be because we haven't
actually saved this properly there we go
and you can see we will fix that in just
a sec let's go back to app.js over here
now what i'm going to do
is i'm going to make sure
right so we've got the sidebar here
perfect from component sidebar and let's
just double check right now we've got
the proper fam like so it's most likely
the color at this point so we'll go
ahead and fix that out so i'm going to
jump into my sidebar and when we have
the sidebar container i'm going to style
that one right now so cyborg container
style div and this one is going to be a
color white but the background color is
going to be the slack color okay so the
first thing we'll do is say background
color variable slack color and there you
go right that's how we do it um
looks fresh okay
so uh faizan i will be dropping react
native dude don't worry um
right an expo you should be using expo
dude if you are working on it until you
need anything else but
there you go color white there we go
and then what i'm going to say is a flex
of 0.3 because i want the sidebar to
only take up 30 so here we're going to
say flex of 0.3
and then you can see now it's taking up
0.3 okay and then what i'm going to say
is a border top of one pixel solid right
and i'm going to say a margin top of 60
pixels now there is a little trick i've
done here okay and what i've done here
is i've actually gone ahead and made
this fixed and there's a reason why
because later on i do this little cool
trick and now with a margin top of 60
pixels it shows okay and there's a
reason why because if you notice in the
final build if we have a long bit of
text right and we do this say hello
world let's just type in hello world
you see how it scrolls down it's a
little trick that we're doing to keep
the top it where it is okay so thank you
so much great energy appreciate it dude
so let's carry on
so at this point
let's keep going and we're going to have
a bunch of horizontal rows and we're
going to target that in a sec but we'll
leave it for now so at this point i
don't get this to look like this okay
because it they definitely don't look
like that right now
um what we need to do
is i'm gonna go ahead and firstly
next to the sidebar info i'm gonna get
that icon so it's called the create icon
and we need to import that from material
ui so i need to go to the top and say
import create icon from material ui
save now refresh and we should be able
to see the little pencil okay so let's
go ahead and make this um look in the
exact way we need to like this one over
here because that looks clean that looks
ugly okay we want to make it look a lot
better okay so
here what i'm going to do is i'm going
to go ahead and say let me turn my mic
gain down there we go i'm going to say
cyborg container and we've already
started this one out the next one we'll
do sidebar header okay so the for the
sidebar header i'm going to simply go
ahead and jump over to my my start
component where is it down here and i'm
going to give this one the following
we'll say display flex and it's gonna
have a border bottom so let me go ahead
and just grab this i'm gonna say display
flex or the bottom padding bottom and a
padding around it okay
there we go let's just chuck that in
and this actually eradicates this one so
we can go ahead and get rid of that and
you can see now it's somewhat got a
similar structure but the text isn't the
same okay now we have an icon here this
one
right now display flex made it into a
row which is why this is now on the
right of this okay if you guys know
peter mckinnon you'll know what this
song is about right this is where it's
about it's where it's from
um
so i'm going to do material ui svg so
i'm going to target the inner material
ui icon and then in here i'm going to
give this icon a padding of 8 pixels a
color a font size a border radius so it
has a nice little circle behind it and a
background color of white and we should
with these rules get it to look like
this let's go ahead and give that a try
boom save
kapow there we go looks good right i
like that i think that looks really nice
the next thing i want to do is we have
sidebar info now sidebar info is this
bit i want this to essentially look like
this okay so let's go ahead and make it
that way okay so we will have redux
inside of zero to full stack hero dude
so we have a sale one right now first
link in the description make sure you
capitalize on that because it's gonna
the doors are gonna close after that man
i can't i can't even say it enough
all right
so i'm gonna go over to the sidebar info
and i'm gonna start this one i'm gonna
say flex one
right flex on that [ __ ] and then here
i'm gonna say h2
and then i'm gonna go ahead and say here
i want a font size of 15 pixels font
weight of 900 and a margin bottom of
five pixels okay
so let's go ahead and do this
save all right so uh faizan dude again i
do want everyone man i do want everyone
to say like don't spam david says sonny
can you include things like formwork yes
i actually did do that inside of my
gmail clone
um so you can check no did i didn't use
formic but i used um
i used the react hooks form which has
validation inside of it so if you're
interested in that dude david check out
my gmail clone the original gmail clone
all right let's go say h3 i don't care i
built that [ __ ] it's gonna say display
flex
and then what we're gonna do is say font
size 13 font size 13.
um and i would say font weight to 400 a
line item center right
so let's go ahead and do this boom
there we go save
and then oh my one's in the house what's
up babe
my gorgeous girlfriend's in the house
and yeah i actually had a bad issue but
we're back now okay so i'm going to
target this is the thing that i like by
the way so i have a h3 tag and if you
see over here i have a h3 and inside of
it i have that material ui icon okay so
usually you have to do some janky weird
stuff in css right but this is pretty
clean taran please don't spam dude all
right so here what i'm going to say is
target the h3
see later gwen
and i'm going to target the material ui
svg root icon go ahead and grab that
and then here i'm going to go ahead and
have the font size
uh i'm going to go ahead and font size
14 margin top one pixel margin right two
pixels and a color of green and you'll
notice that this will suddenly change
into a beautiful looking icon and it'll
have that sort of you know that signed
in look and feel to it okay so that's
exactly what i wanted right there right
now if you notice look at that looks
pretty damn good to me okay
now the reason why this is a little bit
different is because we have this chat
component on the right but we will get
there okay we're going to get to that
point guys let's hit 400 likes if you're
watching right now and you haven't
smashed the thumbs up button smash it
because it's going to help this video
get to as many people as possible with
that said quick wall break
what's up rishi he's watching on um
richie lola
laura sorry dude i always get it wrong
uh he's watching on twitch let's go
okay so at this point i'm gonna go ahead
and have
over here we have the create icon so the
sidebar header is essentially complete
okay so we have the header which is
essentially complete now down here we're
gonna have a reusable component and
we're gonna call this one this sidebar
option
okay it's a sidebar option so i already
have my coffee thank you so much dude um
so cyber options so i'm gonna go ahead
and create that right now so i'm gonna
open up my code go into my components
folder and you can see your sites look
pretty clean okay let's say sidebar
option.js
i'm going to hide that rfce
boom right let's go ahead whoa nigeria
in the house what's up man
and then here again you can see like you
start getting into a flow of it right
i'm going to say cons sidebar option
container
and we'll say equals star div right star
div and you just want to go ahead and
get you know like that muscle memory up
i always say like it's not you don't
have to be the best coder you just need
to get that pattern recognition and you
slowly figure things out guys
i don't remember everything off the top
of my head i don't think i don't i
really don't expect any developer to but
you want to go ahead and make sure you
just take the time to ingrain that
muscle memory okay like because it does
make a difference okay it's very
important um
practice will lead to that okay so at
this point we have our sidebar over here
now what we're gonna do is have a bunch
of these sidebars now these are gonna
have two props okay i want to pass in a
prop which is the icon itself and i want
to pass in the title which is going to
be like this the title mentions and
reactions and so forth and each
individual icon now what i've actually
done here is i'll show you how i want
this to look so let's assume i had all
of these right in so inside my code so
just to save some time i've actually
gone ahead and imported those already
now in react you can have each component
can take props right now props are
properties they allow
dax says it's gonna be recorded yes dude
it's gonna be recorded um
and it will allow a component to render
with slight differences based on the
properties that you pass in okay so at
this point let's go ahead and paste
right so i've got this right here and
you guys can see that we've just got a
bunch of these and each one is getting a
different icon and it's getting a
different title now i will show you how
to consume that in just a sec but let's
go ahead and first import all of those
icons as necessary okay so it's going to
be from the to all the way to expand
all right so i'm gonna go ahead and grab
a bunch of icons and import them okay so
you can pause the video there watch it
if you need to get those icons now at
this point what we should see is cyborg
option is not defined okay so obviously
it makes sense all right we need to go
to cyber option hit save and then i need
to go to sidebar and go ahead and do my
little go to the end of the component
control spacebar
and there we go and see the second one
is a source component sidebar option
that actually does an auto import trick
okay iman says fire bro thank you so
much dude appreciate you watching let's
go ahead and do that now you can see
look it loads right now nothing's on the
screen so we're gonna go ahead and make
sure something actually shows up on the
screen okay guys just hit 400 likes come
on we can do it i know it we can keep
pushing this stuff right so
what we're going to do is we have the
icon then we have the title thread so in
this case what i want to do here is i
want to actually consume this as
something called props like i mentioned
before so perhaps comes through as a
simple function argument okay so at this
point what i want to do
is i'm going to go ahead and do i'm
going to destructure which means i'm
essentially going to go ahead and tear
apart right i'm gonna basically go ahead
and tear apart the object okay so i'm
gonna go ahead and pull apart the object
at this point i'm gonna pull the icon
out and the title this is called
destructuring okay uh robert there is
actually all the code inside the github
repo um but we need to kind of move a
little faster than this one so uh let's
carry on dude so this point um rather
than sidebar container a sidebar option
actually that's good we can keep it as
that okay so i'm gonna go ahead and jump
in
right so now at this point what i'm also
going to do is there we go that's fine
actually we've got icon and title
so you can see we're actually passing in
a whole icon here right so and that's
the reason why this is a capital i not a
lowercase i because we're going to be
rendering it on the screen in just a sec
now inside of here right what i'm going
to do is i'm going to have a few things
in there so i'm going to say okay if you
passed in an icon right so we're going
to protect ourselves
then i'm going to render the icon out
okay it's a self-closing component and
all of these icons in material ui take a
font size and then we can give that a
font size of small okay
now
here i'm actually going to give it an
inline style because it's a bit hard to
do a uh
a styled component in that use case so
i'm going to say just give it a padding
of 10 for each of these right so there
we go now at this point you can see all
the icons have just popped in
so it's looking pretty good at this
point right so and the reason why i put
icon and is because you might actually
render the component now without passing
in an icon okay so the second thing i'm
gonna say is okay if you pass the icon
then what i'm gonna say is i'm gonna go
ahead and render
a h3 which has the tie tool okay so here
i'm gonna say okay jsx with the squiggly
brackets i'm gonna say title like this
and here is we're using a ternary
operator so this basically means if if
icon is truthy so if it's true or if it
has a value inside of it render this out
otherwise render out whatever in this
side of in this parentheses so at this
point what i'm gonna do is i'm gonna go
ahead and create a sidebar option
channel um div okay so this is actually
gonna be a start component
and i'm gonna create this over here so
i'm gonna copy that
i'm gonna go ahead and
grab this line
and then i'm also going to go ahead and
boom
there we go cyber option channel there
we go now at this point we have this div
star div there and i'm just going to
span a hashtag here right i'm going to
span a hashtag and i'm going to have the
title over here and there's a reason why
we're doing this now it'll make a lot of
sense in just a sec okay so i'm going to
go ahead and hit save code with yog says
awesome build please call out my name
yeah i got you dude guys 180 people
watching this is huge right now we
actually have 200 across all the
platforms smash that thumbs up button
please if you're enjoying this because
it's going to help the video help more
people and that's what we do in the papa
fam if you're interested in joining
first link in the description sale ends
in two days and i'm closing the doors
for that yeah that's how it is abhishek
what's up dude
right
so at this point you can see look this
is how it's looking right i don't want
it to look like this i want to look a
little bit cleaner than this so
how do i style it to look in that way so
i'm going to go to the sidebar option
container and the first thing we'll say
is display flex now i do want to see my
code so i'm going to go ahead and make
it like this i'm going to say display
flex okay save and you can see
everything goes into a row okay hey
maven's here she goes yes guys hold on
sunny sunny let's go for food after
yeah honestly i got
the headache this gave me that one
called me up and i gave her i was a bit
grumpy because uh you know the the
stream cut but thank you babe for
sticking in right so at this point we'll
say display flex font size
of 12 pixels and then i'm going to say
align items center
okay line item center padding left of
two pixels
a padding left of two pixels
all right so two pixels like this and
then i'm going to say a cursor pointer
because i want all of these to be like
somewhat course of as you hover over it
right you can say sorry i'm sorry okay
there we go i'm sorry for being grumpy
papa react is kind of grumpy at times
guys
so there you go
all right i'm gonna say okay when i
hover over it i want to change the
opacity right so in order to do that
what i do
is
i
it i'm now she's taking the neck alright
so opacity 0.9 i'm gonna change the
background color when i hover over it
okay so
let's go ahead and refresh
and then you see that guys look at that
fresh okay look at that looks good
looks pretty clean now you can see over
here look we're almost there and it's
looking pretty good at this point okay
so what i'm gonna do is i'm gonna target
the h3 right now the h3 sits over here
okay so in order to grab it again start
components makes this so easy we can say
h3 grab it i'm going to say a font
weight because i want to reduce the
boldness of that text i'm going to say
it should be a 500 sort of weight okay
so 500 is somewhat of an average rate
you can see it drops the font size a
little bit more okay so after we've done
the h3 i'm going to jump into the h3 and
i'm going to jump into a span tag and as
you can remember over here we had a span
for the hashtag there's a reason why i
spam the hashtag it's because i only
want to style the that one hashtag right
i just want to go ahead and uh yeah all
right so uh now i see uh augustine says
wow the engine this platform is mad
exactly dude that's what we're about
honestly it's just you know we just have
fun here man padding of 15 pixels okay
that's it
and uh and we code right we code
properly that's how we do it right so
look at that that looks clean man i like
that that looks pretty good so at this
point what we're going to do is i'm
going to go back up to my code and now
we have this reusable component okay so
it looks pretty good at this point um
what was very useful about this is that
we actually made it so that if we don't
pass an icon in we can just use the type
we can just render our title now why is
that handy because if you wanted to have
it like you can pretty much have it as
just like channels without an icon so
it's a nice way of doing it okay so what
we can do is i'm gonna go back to
sidebar and over here so i'm gonna go
ahead and make that a bit smaller so you
guys can see it there we go
over here what i'm gonna say is where we
have sidebar option
michael what's up dude michael actually
won
uh a prize inside of um
i think it was a second place michael so
congrats dude inside the netflix
challenge absolutely smashed it did so
here i'm going to drop horizontal lines
okay so you see over in this build we
have the horizontal lines coming in
clutch over here and here so i'm going
to go ahead and do the same thing over
in our build okay so i'm going to say
horizontal line
and then you can see over here it just
looks pretty ugly at that point but
we'll style it right we'll make it
better
and then i'm gonna have another cyber
option okay so i don't know why that
jumped over there i'm gonna have another
cyber option with the expand more icon
and the title is gonna be channels and
this is what the beauty right this is
the real beauty of the um
this is the beauty of style component of
reusable components okay and style
components i guess because we're using
both of them but it's really really
clean because reasonable components like
if you do them well you can code so fast
right because you don't have to repeat
yourself it also makes it a lot easier
to maintain your code base okay so this
is really good guys come on almost at
400 likes let's go
all right so i'm going to drop another
horizontal row over here so boom we
should have another line and then what
i'm going to do is i'm going to have an
add icon channel right so here i'm going
to have another ad icon and this has
another prop called add channel option
okay and i'll show you what we do with
that one in just a sec but if i go ahead
and save that now it's going to freak
out because we didn't import ad icon so
i'm going to go ahead and pull in add
icon from
material ui like so save
and then what i'm going to do is refresh
and you can see that the go here would
be all of these buttons are actually
clickable right so i can click them and
all that sort of stuff and then this one
if i click it it says please enter a
channel name so we want some
functionality behind it how do i
determine when to sort of pop this up i
pass another prop and you guessed it
that prop is going to be the add channel
option so if i go over to sidebar option
i'm going to pull that in as a prop okay
and we'll sort of set that up in just a
sec
okay
perfect now at this point right we have
the channels over here and then we have
the final bit underneath now the last
bit is actually the channels which
render out so if i was to go ahead and
add a channel saying um
let's just say
let's just say pop fam all right just to
say pop fam okay and you can see like a
channel came in here so this one we need
to go ahead and actually
sort of set up with a database behind it
okay so this is actually sort of uh oh
nice classes guys come on energy from
twitch nice um
yeah so you can you see this can be set
up to a database we're gonna go ahead
and configure that in just a sec okay so
what i'm gonna do at this point is i'm
going to go ahead and style out the hr
right so i'm going to go into my sidebar
over here
and i'm going to go ahead and say start
bar
sorry sidebar container and i'm going to
target the horizontal row which is that
line and i'm going to give it a margin
top 10 pixels margin bottom and a border
of one pixel solid and it's got a nice
little color to it you guys will see in
just a sec boom there we go very subtle
okay very very subtle stuff and then
what we're gonna do
is the we've already done the header
we've already done that blah blah blah
nice that actually looks pretty damn
good okay so at this point if i go ahead
and show you guys look at this
that's pretty damn close right so we're
looking pretty good at this point
okay
now what we want to do
is i actually want to firstly create
these rooms
okay so how do we create the rooms right
so
oh nice
london uk oh [ __ ]
i'm in london dude right so uh let's go
ahead and say
at this point boom just go and pop this
halfway put this halfway nice
okay
so inside of sidebar option what i'm
going to do is i'm going to have a add
channel now what's really cool here
is that i'm going to basically have it
so that if you click on this one you add
a channel if you click on this one
you're selecting a channel okay so in
this case if i if i click on this one it
selects the channel okay it takes a
little second because the internet's a
bit slow but if i go ahead and for
example add a channel how do i do that
right how do i make it sort of dependent
on on that sort of thing so
the way i do that is i go ahead let me
just make this small for a sec and then
we make this a bit bigger so we go ahead
we take our add channel option prop now
we go to our
sidebar option container and what i
simply do is i say okay
attach and on click right uh but if i
have add channel option passed as a prop
i'm going to trigger off the add channel
function which we need to write or if
that's actually not there we don't
actually see this prop in there or it's
falsies so which means it's not got a
value behind it i'm gonna select a
channel instead now these two functions
i need to create add channel and select
channel okay so almost at 400 likes guys
smash the thumbs up button we're almost
almost there okay now at this point i'm
going to create two functions we're
going to create one which is const add
channel
and this is going to be an anonymous
function i'm going to do the same thing
for select channel i'm going to say con
select channel
boom an anonymous function like so
that's it right we've got two two
different functions over there
and uh yeah you shouldn't have any
errors inside your code at this point
everything should be looking good 400
likes
literally one like away come on guys
let's do it literally we're almost
flipping 500 likes and we literally lost
200 from a technical glitch
that's what i'm talking about guys thank
you so much we just hit 400 likes
incredible stuff incredible incredible
stuff that's what the proper fans about
just want to say one more time
cell wins in two days to join the pop
fam god damn guys
don't miss out first link in the
description christopher made the choice
today to join us and he will not regret
it dude that's what i'm talking about
i love how you know you wait for that
one like and then it's like boom 10
likes
right that's what i'm talking about
that's the kind of energy we need dude
like where was those where were those
people they're just like waiting on
standby like i'm gonna i'm gonna be that
person that gets one and then everyone
decides to jump and it's like boom you
know how it is all right
all right let's carry on guys so at this
point we have got the ad channel okay so
for the ad channel we're gonna do a few
cool things so now what i need to do is
set up firebase okay so i'm gonna go
over to my files earlier and remember we
added in the firebase configuration okay
so what i actually need to do is command
j pull out my terminal i'm gonna say
yarn add firebase
all right so yes because we're going to
install firebase into our project now
while it's doing that i can go over here
and i can say
import firebase from firebase mahmed
says hey sunny great what man thank you
so much dude uh sharika let's do it dude
let's get 500 i think we can do it
right now what we're going to say is
while that's installing i already know
it's right we're going to say firebase
app equals firebase which is our package
we just installed dot initialize app and
the way you set up the app and basically
what this is doing is it connects the
the front end that we're building right
now to firebase so firebase is the thing
that's powering everything it's google's
sort of back-end servers and basically
right now initialize app is going to
take that configuration and connect
these two things together all right and
it makes everything work in the way we
expect so here i'm going to say firebase
config
okay and then i'm going to go ahead and
say const db because i need access to
the database now what database am i
referring to you guys you might be
wondering so i'm going to go over to my
firebase i'm going to go into over here
and i'm going to say cloud firestore
okay so cloud firestore over here victor
uh newbleen says you deserve 1 million
subscribers dude we're not going to stop
until we get there so i'm telling you
just keep on going right next right now
let's go ahead and hit 500 likes that's
the sort of you know we celebrate all
this morning you want to click on create
database start in test mode click next
here you want to click name enable
that's fine all good
right
so once that's done
this will go ahead and set up firestore
right firestore is a real-time database
now it's so powerful it's real time
which means as messages come through
it'll be so easy to implement we're
going to go ahead and do it really
nicely right now okay so it says cannot
enable after you set it though oh
interesting let's have a look why i
might actually have to use if it if you
can't enable it i'll
i'll go ahead and and use a different
account that's completely cool
all right so setting up security rules
let's out of that
okay it did that so if you get that
arrow just go ahead and do it right so
at this point what i'm going to do is uh
and guys this is not a gossip channel
dude so please don't all right so what
we're going to do is we're going to go
ahead and this is basically a nosql
structure right now what does a nosql
structure look like right nosql pretty
much has a structure of collection
right and a collection can have several
documents okay so it'll have several
documents now if you don't know about
this stuff i really recommend you look
into what nosql databases are like and
then after a document like you'll have
several documents so imagine our
collection was let's say rooms right so
chat rooms okay every single document
would represent a different room like a
different chat room okay now each room
will have its own collections you see it
takes a collection document collection
structure so this one would be a
collection
and then in here you would have a
collection of messages right so this one
would be like for example would be a
collection of messages and then this
would lead to a
literally again so it would lead to
all the messages in the form of document
like documents okay so here you would
have all the different messages for this
chat room so you see you have a
collection of rooms the rooms themselves
each room will have its own collection
of messages and then these will be
rendered out as documents okay so that's
how it kind of works when you're using
nosql okay so at this point what we're
gonna do black knight says just finished
netflix day three challenge i came here
for the new build that's what i'm
talking about dude coming in clutch man
so at this point we've got the database
how do i access it okay i say firebase
app i basically grab this paste it cause
i'm lazy and then i say dot firestore
right no no i don't i say firebase app
yeah dot firestore yeah i do
almost got lost there right and then i'm
gonna say const auth because we have a
sign in in this app so i'm gonna say
firebase.org and this is how we do it
now how do i get google authentication
right what i do is i add in something
called a provider now all you need to do
is add in this line right here what this
does is it gets the google
authentication provider which is a nice
little pop-up ready for us okay
so what i do now is i go over to my
firebase and i go to authentication the
tab over here click it
all right this is insane right that's
what i'm saying guys honestly like the
power of the papa phone we have
literally uh 170 people watching across
different platforms right now and we
have 421 likes like that's just that
just shows you how powerful this damn
community is right like it's incredible
like i don't see any other channel doing
this right now authentication click get
started and then here very simple to get
this up and running okay what you want
to do is you want to go to google hit
this button enable and then you want to
click on a project support email save
that's how you enable google
authentication guys it's literally that
simple i promise you and it's even
easier now because we're using firebase
hooks and they're gonna be your best
friend i swear to god guys let's hit 500
likes come on it's gonna be so fun all
right so we've got this right up now
running okay so
this looks pretty good
and what i'm gonna do now is i need to
export this stuff so that we can use it
outside so i'm going to say export
and i'm going to exploit explicitly i'm
going to export the authentication the
provider and the db this means that i
can access the db from anywhere i can
access the authentication and i can
access a little pop-up anywhere okay so
this is going to be uh really important
work says i learn more from sunny than
in university dude that's what i'm
talking about man that's what i want to
do you know that's my mission to just
drive a value right let's get this
energy back up quick water break if you
guys are having a water break then uh
join me right now
and let's let's have it together
sounded weird but you know
[Music]
all right
change the lighting a little bit
change a little tempo to this right
let's carry on guys
okay
so at this point we're gonna go ahead
and jump into our sidebar option
okay say to say teacher t break four
axes nice red bull break oh i don't know
it's dangerous for me dude six o'clock
i do want to sleep tonight
all right so at this point what we're
going to do is i'm going to actually add
in so firstly we're going to do the add
channel now how do we add a channel to
that database structure that i showed
you earlier before we actually do that i
want to add i want to show you guys a
little trick okay so if you go to rules
over here now don't do this in
production environments this is only for
demos or something on your portfolio
that don't really matter but i'm going
to make it so that anyone can read and
write to this database you shouldn't do
that for production okay if you should
only have it and i'm not gonna go into
the security rules right now but it's
very important that you don't do that in
production environments let's go ahead
and go back to data so how do i go ahead
and add rooms right so what rooms am i
talking about exactly i'm talking about
these rooms so like youtube papa fam
papa how do you get all these different
channels right
and eventually if you guys stick it to
the end you will be able to actually go
ahead and jump onto the chat we can all
have a chat through the app which would
be pretty cool okay fantanus is still in
love with that water bottle honestly
dude i love this what well
i have so many of these um so i'm gonna
say add channel and then here what i'm
gonna do is i'm gonna say okay
what i'm gonna do is i'm gonna say const
channel name and how do i get the
channel name right what i'm going to do
is i'm going to say prompt okay so i'm
actually going to prompt the user and
that's actually built in so we can say
please enter the channel name right so
please enter the channel
name okay now what you want to do is
whenever you prompt the user you need to
protect against the empty so some people
might go ahead and prompt but then go
ahead and
enter it without value or you want to
protect against that uh this is a pre
this is a more upgraded version of the
previous slack clone yes so here we say
if and then we say channel name
right if channel name and if the channel
name has a value then we access the
database because basically remember that
firebase that we the configuration we
set up earlier then we exported it so
i'm going to pull in my database
and i'm just going to say and i'm
importing it from my local firebase file
i'm going to say db dot collection and
the collection is going to be the rooms
and what i'm going to do is i'm going to
add a room okay
find heart thank you so much dude i'm
going to add a room and they're
basically adding a room so it's very
simple you add an object right you just
simply go ahead and pop in the name of
this room is going to be the channel
name that i just collected from the
prompt now let's go ahead and see this
in action over on the other one so if we
go ahead and say add a channel and here
you can see if i say like uh let's just
say
uh
coding
enter you can see coding right so how do
i go ahead and do that so
i'm gonna say channel name and hit save
now on our build over here if i go ahead
and hit add channel and i need to
refresh most likely
and what we actually need to do is in
sidebar add channel option i passed it
through
we pass in over here there we go and if
i go ahead and click add channel now
please enter the channel name so if i
say abc emerson says most friendly guy
ever thank you so much guys uh well it's
literally nearly up 450 likes let's go
and let's get okay perfect okay so it
worked in the way we expected it to but
nothing really happened all right saita
just said suddenly i got five jobs wow
oh my god dude just send me brew for
that please
tell me on my instagram i don't know
what it is i love this damn song man
all right so now we pretty much go ahead
and have a nice little prompt at this
point okay
all right so
450 likes let's go man oh my god this
channel was insane honestly let's go
all right so this will go ahead and add
it now i actually just went ahead and
tried that out so let's see if i added
it to database so i'm going to hit
refresh on the cloud firestore database
we should see rooms
rooms there we go and we see abc that
was the room that we just created all
right awesome stuff so we actually went
ahead and pushed it into our back end
okay so that looks really really nice at
this point in time now
how do i actually go ahead and then
list them out on the sidebar though
right so it's all farewell that we add
them but how do i actually use them
now previously we had to use some kind
of jankies effect and if you've ever
seen any of my builds it's kind of a
headache to do that okay so instead what
we're going to be doing now because what
i want to do is i want to have a
real-time listener to that database
which will allow me to basically pull
this in in a real-time fashion okay so
what i'm going to do here
is uh oh nice haha he's shazamed it
thank you dude so what i'm going to do
here is i'm actually going to go ahead
and say um firebase
hooks
and save and you can see react firebase
hooks right you're going to click the
first link and all you need to do to get
this up and running you guys can feel
free to read that documentation but all
i'm going to do is go ahead and command
j yarn add react firebase hooks
so i'm going to install this okay and
this is the one that you want to install
now they have a really great
documentation there and here's the sort
of useful links that show you how to use
each one so the authentication has cloud
files to hooks but you guys are going to
see the absolute crazy power okay you're
going to see honestly the crazy power of
this right now so it's already installed
so we hit command j to hide it and now
what we do is we go to the top of our
file where we typically would have you
know defined some state right but what
we do here is we say const
we want the channels from firestore okay
so something i don't really see what
you're doing here so we're going to get
the channels and what's actually even
better we can get the loading state even
when it's loading and if there's an
error we can actually get the error
state all right so this is getting this
is kind of getting powerful saying what
are you doing here right and then here
we say equals use collection
okay
views collection and some of you
watching like i'm listening i'm kind of
listening was this happening and let's
go ahead and import that right from the
react firebase hooks and then how do we
go ahead and access the collection so
i'm actually going to go ahead and
access this collection right now and i'm
trying to get the channels right which
is actually the rooms right so in this
case
the naming's a bit off but that's what
we're referring to madhu says you have a
lot of energy man thank you so much dude
you guys give me that energy and here
what i do is i say db
right so i'm going to go ahead and pull
in my db which i already have and i will
say db.collection
and i'm just going to point to the rooms
and you better goddamn believe it that
that is it now in channels i have the
collections
so if i go ahead and i just say let's
just do a console log
of channels here and i go ahead and do f
command f12 to show this look at this
guys that is actually
there's actually the uh the channels
right there so if i do docs an array of
one and it looks weird right now but
i'll show you that i'll prove to you
that that is actually what we're looking
for right so this is this is incredible
right this is really really incredible
uh finnair says it's been an hour you're
nearly finished yet you went at a pace
and made me understand thanks a lot
thank you so much man honestly like i
really appreciate the kind words
um surendra recognize me bro
right so let's carry on um
[Music]
and what we're gonna do now is we're
gonna go ahead get rid of that console
log
and i'm gonna go ahead and say so we
have the channels over there right now i
wanna loop through them and show them as
sidebar options okay so how do i do that
what i want to do is each actual sort of
room has an id as well so i will be
passing that as an another additional
prop to my sidebar option but what i
need to do here is go back to sidebar
and i'm going to go over here and i'm
going to say okay
go into the channels right go into the
docs and remember channels can be
undefined in the beginning so we're
going to protect it with something
called optional chaining right then we
say dot right how are you using react
just without having stack overflow open
the next page real programmer respect
thank you dude honestly just practice
takes a lot of practice and uh
my course right once you take it you
understand react inside out all right
there's a sale one by the way guys two
days left first link in description
check it out if you're interested right
here we're gonna say uh
channels.docs.map
okay
uh so all the audiences sees i'm sorry i
didn't pronounce right that's through
them yes i'm gonna map through them dude
so i'm gonna go ahead and say map for
each one and each of the documents what
i'm going to do is i'm going to go ahead
and return something
so what i want to do is i want to return
through this entire list and basically
render out a sidebar option so i'm going
to go ahead and pop a cyber option
obviously i don't want this one i
actually just wanted the i don't want
the icon here what i want instead is i
want to say okay the title
should be
the doc dot data
so i'm going to access the data which is
this
data inside of a document and i'm going
to say dot name which was actually the
name that i gave it here so dot name
right so a little typo dot name okay
that's the first thing now whenever you
have a map inside of react you should
always provide a key right now keys are
very important because it tells react
that you do not need to re-render that
entire list if something gets added in
because
let's say it rendered a thousand
elements in the list and you only want
to you only add in one extra sort of
element to that list because every
single one has a different key now react
knows oh wait a sec you only added
something at the bottom the other 52
that you added before don't need to be
re-rendered so it makes it a lot more
efficient okay
so here i say the key is dot doc id
right and the document id is going to be
this one so at this point what can i do
i can say actually i'm going to pass
through an id which is going to be the
doctor id because i actually need this
id as a prop and i'll show you why okay
i'll show you exactly why
channels is not defined that's because
um oh wait a sec in sidebar options
um oh i've done it in the wrong room
there we go this needs to be inside bar
my bad so this should be inside bar
right now there we go inside bar and
then this means that the use collection
should also be inside bar okay so this
one should also be in here which means
we also need to import db
so make sure you just follow me with
that one there's a slight little change
it should be in sidebar okay harpery
what's up man good to see bro
that's my brother-in-law's that's just
here's my brother in the house there we
go all right
and then here we're gonna say channels
there we go and you got the channels it
says channels is not defined but if we
save now when we refresh should be good
all right so now you can see like the
channels
but ah there we go guys abc there we go
look at that works right i mean it looks
like trash but we'll make it look nice
um so at this point like it does not
look great but we're gonna make that
look a little bit better we're gonna
make that look very clean in the end
okay
so how do i get this to look in the way
that i have option so i'm heading over
to sidebar option i'm passing through
the id
okay so make sure you don't forget that
step is very important now inside the
sidebar option okay
uh that's it harps is in the house man
so what we're gonna do is where we have
the h3 okay so this is going to be the
sidebar option channel so we need to
style sidebar option channel which is
why it looks like trash right now so i'm
gonna go over to sidebar option channel
and
where is that sidebar option channel
there we go okay so this is gonna be a
slight this is not gonna be a div it's
gonna be a h3
okay because this is going to be and a
sort of h3 so you see what we're doing
there's really good right action says
hey son you just joined you are amazing
thank you so much dude uh hardik says
you're on fire thank you man we're
literally about to break 500 likes come
on guys just keep on going it's so so
cool and i love how everyone chats to
each other starts to get to know each
other so nice all right so here i'm
going to say padding
of 10 pixels by zero so 10 pixels by
zero i'm going to say a font weight of
300.
whoa
check out ancho sing he says i have
landed a 100k job thank you that's
it man that's what we do that's what we
do
right
if you if the room's collection has only
an id how did you extract channels um no
so it doesn't have an id these are the
channels this is going to be like a doc
these are all channels so the room all
of these documents would be the channels
and then the doc.data would be the data
inside of each one okay
so let's go ahead and save and then you
see guys that looks pretty clean okay
but you see look at that oh
it shouldn't be triggering it should
only be triggering on the abc
it should it shouldn't be triggering on
this one right so we've got a problem
there so
the problem there is we've got a channel
option but what we need to actually do
is say
select channel
okay
so at this point what we need to do is
say
well we have select channel
so now what i'm going to do is firstly
this should this is oh oops if we go to
sidebar we don't need the add channel
option here we don't want that
we refresh
and you should have it so that only the
ad channel makes the pop-up come up if
you click this one it shouldn't make it
pop up because what we actually want to
do is trigger off the
select channel function okay so there we
go right so now what i'm going to do
is
um curious says uh so this is a much
more upgraded slack clone so this has
style components redox and firebase
hooks so
i love a lot more all right
um
all right let's carry on guys so select
channel so inside the sec channel what
i'm gonna do is this is where i'm gonna
use redux so what i wanna do is every
time we select a room i wanna push the
id into my redux right
now what is redux right redux is like a
global store so
think of our application where every
single component has state which is like
some kind of memory inside of it right
now
if i need some memory to exist and kind
of float around my entire app and i just
need to pull it when i need to redox is
basically it's going to solve that
problem for us it's going to act as
something like a global store it's going
to be like a global place where we can
access and store variables now how do we
push data into redux we dispatch
something called an action which allows
us to manipulate the sort of data which
lies inside the redux slices now what we
do is in today's build we're only going
to have one slice which is just going to
refer to all the app contents but you
can actually divide that global store up
in things that make sense let's say you
had an e-commerce site you could have a
basket slice a user slice and all that
cool stuff okay so a lot a lot to learn
here and it's gonna be a lot of fun okay
so what we're gonna do now is actually
prepare redux and it's gonna be a lot
simpler than you think okay so let's go
ahead and jump into that
so i'm gonna go over to my code
and i'm going to go ahead and say where
we have oh and you'll sing thank you so
much dude
it does not matter if it's uh he says
it's a small donation but dude any
donation is massively appreciated thank
you so much so here we have
um
how's this chatting away to everyone
here we go in app store.js so i want to
rename this to not be the counter
reducer i'm going to rename all of these
things to become app reducer so i'm
going to have one kind of global store
inside of this build but typically you
should spread it out based on like you
know what's in the basket what's in the
sort of user information that sort of
stuff so at this point i need to go to
my
um
i need to go to my features
click that and i'm going to rename
counter slice to become app slice
right app slice there we go right
perfect now i'm going to jump into app
slice and over here what i need to do is
i need to start renaming this so i'm
going to rename these two things to
become app and then i'm going to go here
and this is actually going to become
room id this is the initial state of
that global store right now i just have
a room id which by default in the
beginning is going to be no it's not
going to have a value okay
um right so please don't spam dude um
you're gonna get blocked so sorry about
that dude
um so at this point what i'm gonna do is
i'm gonna go ahead and say
let's go down here i'm gonna get rid of
this increment async there we go boom
and then i'm going to go ahead and
actually change this up a little bit so
where we have features down here
i'm going to change this to have uh sort
of an action and let's think about what
is the action when we click that button
we kind of want to enter the room okay
and by entering the room what i'm going
to do is i'm going to take the id okay
i'm going to take the id of the sort of
the the sidebar option i just click so
the room i'm going to get the id and
basically push it into the store with
the enter room action okay so let's go
ahead and do that right now so i'm gonna
get rid of these two actions we don't
need them right now okay and every
single action inside this reducers
section is these are the actions okay so
i'm gonna go ahead and get rid of this
comment and all we're gonna do here is
essentially go ahead and have i don't
know why my kite just opened up strange
um
so i'm gonna oh
we just hit 500 likes thank you so much
guys that's incredible man 181 people
watching we have 500 likes on this let's
hit 600 now let's keep on going man that
is insane let's keep on going so so cool
honestly and the fact that we had a cut
out with the tech issue
doesn't stop us man like we've got the
whole video up after this build is
finished it's gonna be perfect you know
we don't let this stuff ruin us and guys
as i said before there's a two day sale
left right you have two days to
capitalize on that so first link in the
description christopher made the right
choice today jumped in but anyway guys
congrats we hit 500 let's keep on going
all right so for the enter room action
okay so we're going to say enter room is
going to be our action and this one is
going to have
whenever you dispatch an action you get
the state and you get the action itself
now this will make a lot of sense later
but what we want to do is whenever we
just get that action inside of our state
we're going to say change the room id to
whatever the
action.payload.room id is
okay and this will make a lot of sense
once we go ahead and break this down and
again redux can be scary guys it can be
scary but don't freak out about it we're
going to break it down it'll make a lot
of sense okay abdul says i was the one
who did the 500 can i get a shout out
there you go i did right
so we need to export this so that way we
can use it outside so firstly we're
going to change counter to app slice
we're going to go here to get rid of
these and we're going to make it enter
room so now that we can use this enter
room outside of the
uh app slice component as in function
okay so these are called selectors now
so once we push a value into the global
store how do i basically remember i said
you dispatch an action which goes ahead
and changes a bit of the store how do i
now grab that bit of data the room id
from the global store right we have
something called a selector selectors
are really important you need to learn
them and this is how you write a
selector so we're going to say select
room id oops select room id so select
room id and this will have the state or
have access to the state it goes into
state dot app but i mean it's defined by
app because this is the app slice and
then here we're going to say
estate.app.room
id right perfect and we just got 20
likes insane stuff dude honestly crazy
crazy stuff right um so now what i'm
going to do
is go ahead and say export default
app slice there we go okay appstore
reducer now everything should be clean
here right so if we hit save and we go
back to our application and let's go
ahead and see no errors that's what we
want to see okay so i'm going to go
ahead and double check let's go to our
sidebar option now so
i've went ahead and i've i can push into
the database successfully but i want to
go ahead and remember when i click one
of these for example this one i need to
push that room id into
the
into the um one sec let me see uh yeah
i'm going to push that id into the redux
store now true youngs has a good
question so he says hi sonny love what
you're doing thank you dude i have one
question what's the difference between
using redux and the data layer they
approach used in the last
slack clone so big difference honestly
and what we're going to basically be
saying is firstly ellie no we will not
be using it but don't spam please
yes
between redux and daily so they are both
essentially global stores right but
redux is the sort of commercial level
solution to state management okay you
need to know redux if you're going to be
a react developer it's pretty much used
in a lot of the companies you're going
to find yourself working at so you do
need to have this on your cv and it's
going to be a hugely valuable skill to
have okay so definitely recommend you
pick this skill up right so at this
point we're going to go ahead and click
this and we want to dispatch it so that
when we click this it goes ahead and
fires off select channel because this
does not have the prop add channel
option okay so what i'm going to do now
is and i just answered that question
dude so
oh my god solution size thank you so
much for your videos i'm just 17 i
earned more than my parents do i'm
grateful to have you as my teacher
that's incredible guys honestly i think
we're going to break 600 likes in select
channel right now what i'm going to do
with the select channel is i'm going to
go ahead and do
i'm going to say okay if there is an id
all right so if we get an id posture as
a prop and the only one with ids right
now is the these ones because they're
the ones we mapped through from the
database these ones didn't have an id
and then what we're going to say is if
there's an id i want to dispatch an
action into that global store so firstly
we need like something that allows us to
dispatch
that action into the global store so we
use
we need to get the dispatch sort of i
call it like a dispatch gun it allows us
to shoot actions into the global store
okay so i say const dispatch equals use
dispatch which is a fantasy hook
provided by the react uh redux devtools
so let's go ahead and import that and
you see use dispatch from react redux
we pretty much do that now we've got
this little gun that we can shoot
actions into the store okay
so um there we go so now we're gonna do
is go ahead and say if id i'm gonna say
dispatch right and remember we created
an enter room function right so i'm
gonna type in enter room and i'm gonna
import it from our features right
remember this was the action that we
went ahead and done remember that took
something called a payload okay that
took a payload right uh ronit says i got
an internship on react looking for
you're helping up coin days do you join
zero to full stack hero the whole
community will help you and me right so
we're going to pass a payload here which
is we put the parentheses we put an
object and inside of here what i'm going
to say is i'm going to pass in the room
id and that's going to be the um
let's think about this going to be the
id right of the the component so the id
here now what's happening is when we
click this button it will push
that value of the room id or the channel
id into the global store and basically
think about what we're doing here that's
going to be the channel that we're
actively going to be inside of so if i
click this one it clicks the id for that
it pushes the id for this inside the
global store if i click coding it pushes
that into the global store right and
this is empty right now so if i say
hello see it's a fresh chat if i do papa
fam it'll go ahead switch out papa fam's
empty as well hashtag papa let's do
proper farm legends
let's do youtube and you see it's just
pushing different values for the rooms
into the global store and then we use
that value to go ahead and fetch the
messages inside the room all right so at
this point what we're going to do
is we're going to go ahead and vikram
wanted a quick look over the uh sidebar
container so i'm going to take a quick
water break where you see that
thank you shaker keep yourself hydrated
they actually do need reminders when i'm
live
right so what i'm going to do now is i'm
going to go ahead and say
on the slack channel so we actually went
ahead and added this in right so what
i'm going to show you is just to prove
that this works you can download the
redux dev tools and what's amazing about
the redox devtools if i go ahead and
open the inspector i pull down this
redux tab so you need to install redux
devtools on google chrome um and then
let's go ahead and click abc
right and right now oh nothing's
happening okay so let's see why let's go
ahead and do it again just because i
didn't refresh but if i click here it
dispatched an action now the action came
from the app slice right we dispatched
the enter room action
and now if i click on diff it shows me
how it modified the global store so you
can see it went into the app store it
went into the room and room was
initially know as the default value and
it changed it to the room id now if i go
ahead and see the action it was
dispatched this was the action that was
dispatched this was the payload of the
action and now if we check the overall
app store so imagine the global store
this is how we look at it inside the
state we can go ahead click inside and
we can see inside our app now we have
the room id it's currently selected this
is how it works inside of redox okay if
that if you can grasp that concept it
honestly doesn't get harder than that
when it comes to redux okay like
honestly that's the main grasp of it
everything else can kind of come from
that okay
so let's go ahead and continue on
now what we're gonna do that we have the
room id
we're gonna go ahead and uh let's just
firstly test if we can add a second
channel let's say papa fab
oops papa
and there you go you see now if i go
ahead and open this up
i can go into redux
and i can click on the different ones
and you see every time i click and
what's crazy guys is you can actually
rewind so that i can jump back to these
things
i can rewind and i can actually like
kind of like fast forward my application
which is insane
right you can see like every time i
click it it changes the room id
so you see how it's working under the
hood right now okay
all right so this is actually pretty
good so ankit says sonny can you please
use uh style components instead of
normal css and upcoming clones it gives
so much value in learning stuff yes dude
i would definitely make sure i
incorporate them
uh we're actually using it today right
so
okay so that's pretty cool now now we
have the ability to select the channel
so at this point we are done with the
sidebar right and we're literally six
likes away from five c 550 so whoever is
those six people you know what to do
right smash that like button let's get
that number up i swear to god i think we
can honestly keep climbing there's
nothing that's going to stop us today um
and what song should we have right now
let's go ahead and have something a
little bit upbeat
right
so
now what we're going to do is actually
have the chat section right because
we've already got the room id now so i
guess we can start actually implementing
the messages inside of the chat right
now the chat where is the chat defined
so we go into app.js you can see chat
was over here inside of the home route
okay so chat refers to this big section
over here right so we're going to go
ahead and build that out right now okay
so the first thing i'm going to do is
i'm going to go ahead and say
um
battle sword i have connected it
i've just done it in a new way right so
i'm going to create a chat component
and i'm going to go ahead and say in
components i'm going to say chat.js
i'm going to say rfce
and then here inside of here what i'm
going to do is chat container so i'm
going to go and say cons
chat
container
equals styled div
boom boom
and there you go and i'm going to go
ahead and
pull in styled from start components i
don't know why it's not popping up on my
auto sort of my import it was working
before but that's fine we gotta do it
manually that's fine
save okay now what i'm gonna do is say
this is a chat container
oops chat container there we go right
perfect so we have the chat container up
and running now i'm gonna go back into
my app.js and then make sure i've
imported this component in to our
application so there we go chat gets
popped in right there okay so at this
point to just double check that
everything's working i'm gonna open up
chat.js and i'm gonna go ahead and say
h1 i am the chat screen
save
and we should see it's not there right
now is actually there but we just need
to go ahead and get the color and things
like that set up correctly so the first
thing i want to do is actually open up
the chat screen and it's actually up
here at the top so i'm going to go ahead
and show you how to fix that let's open
the chat screen
i'm going to go to my chat container and
the first thing i want to do is i'm
going to type in i'm going to say flex
0.7
oops save
i'm saying flex 0.7 because i want to
take up 70 on the screen flex grow of 1
and overflow y scroll okay so i'm going
to go ahead and do this right here
save okay now at this point i'm going to
save and if you can see if i go ahead
and spam this i'll show you what's
actually happening you see it's actually
underneath the header at the point at
this point in time okay so i'll show you
how we're going to fix this in a bit
all right let's go ahead and save right
so at this point the let's go ahead and
firstly do
inside of the chat screen right so
we have
the first thing we're going to do
is we have
the chat itself so the first thing i
need to actually do is pop a margin in
there so i can see it so if i do h1
let's just say hello okay and what i
need to do is i'm gonna see margin top
i should do ten let's just try and do 50
pixels we need to get that right so we
can see it there we go so 50 is about
right let's say 40 maybe
nope it's a uh 60.
there we go we'll try that one for now
okay so there we go we can see it okay
so at this point what i'm going to do is
i'm going to fetch the room information
okay so we firstly need to go ahead and
have the room details now what am i
talking about the room details um i'll
show you in just a sec so
what i'm gonna firstly do is i'm gonna
go ahead and say
let's go ahead and create a header
section at the top okay so at the top of
this file we're gonna have a header okay
we're gonna have a header and i'm gonna
create this as a
styled component so here i'm gonna say
thank you so much jason sure i
appreciate it dude let's go ahead and
hit 600 likes guys come on we can do
this
style.div
right and then here what i'm going to do
is go ahead and do the following so i'm
going to say start div and then this is
going to be we'll start that in just a
sec inside of this header i'm going to
have a header left and a header right
and this will make a lot of sense just
bear with me okay so we've got the
header left and we've got a header right
right so header oops
i don't wait okay and now what i'm going
to do is go and create the styled
component versions of these i'm going to
say const at the left equals style.div
right like so we have authentication we
have everything inside this board coming
very soon okay
so
i'm gonna go ahead and copy this one and
we'll say header or right
and then we go save right there we go
looks good now what i'm gonna do is
we've got header left header right so
the header left is gonna have a h4
inside of it
all right so it's gonna have a h4
so this is gonna be a h4 oops h4
kite keeps opening up soon so annoying
right h4 and then here i'm gonna say
strong
i'm gonna have a strong bit of text
which is strong not string
yeah and then in here what i'm gonna
have is a hashtag and this will be the
room name okay so i'm gonna go ahead and
sort of fix this up with the room name
in a second i'll show you how we do that
in a sec
and then the next thing i'm gonna do is
actually have a little star icon okay
so i'm gonna say
boom star border outline okay
let's go ahead and say star border
outline
paste
what accent is this man this is a london
accent and then there you go you see it
says the room name okay so now i can get
rid of the h1 hello
and this top bit is gonna be the room
name okay so at this point we're gonna
go ahead and pop out the header right
section and then we'll go ahead and do
the fancy styling stuff to get this
finished okay so inside of header right
i simply want a p tag and i'm going to
have an info outline icon and it's going
to say details next to it so it
shouldn't say p
p there we go and it's going to say
something
details okay so it's going to have this
and it's going to say details and info
outlined i kind of show you what that is
in just a sec
i'm going to go ahead and pour this into
my code at the top there we go save
and if we refresh there you go
all right so that looks pretty good
pretty clean right now now i'm going to
go ahead and fix this up so it looks
very nice because right now i don't like
how it looks okay so here how do i get
this looking the way i need it i'm going
to say header equal style dot star dip
and say display flex firstly
right this one gets me hyped up man
let's go ahead and smash the like button
and get 600 guys come on
display flex
justify
content
space between
right and then i'm going to say padding
of 20 pixels or border bottom
boom i'm going to chuck that in here
all right save and now you guys can see
that immediately huge difference right
huge huge difference right right so now
what we're going to do these are
actually not these are not in inline
styles these are actually going to be uh
yeah
so at this point we're going to say
header left
um and the funny the funny thing i
always find is that every like sometimes
people actually demand things live i'm
like dude i don't think you realize how
much we're building in this live session
right so here what i'm going to say is
i'm going to target the h4 inside
because we have the little h4 at the top
and then what i'm going to do is say
display flex
right display flex and then here i'm
going to say text transform lowercase
right
save and there you can see it drops to a
lowercase and i'm going to then target
the h4 and the icon inside so similar to
the approach we've done before targeting
the material ui i can margin left in a
font size
let's go ahead and do that right now
there we go looks pretty good okay so
the next thing we can do at this point
is we're going to go ahead and i think
we should also maybe say display flex on
that
let's go ahead and do this oops that's a
horrible world let's go ahead and do
that fx and there you go you can see
that let's play flex and what i actually
want to do here is to say
um
let's go ahead and say the margin left
is there but i'm going to align items
align item center
and oops no what is that doing nope
you got line item center and there you
go right so it looks very nice we can
actually sort of push that slightly more
away with the 20 pixel push
and there we go okay so that's not
actually targeted that one correctly so
we need to go ahead and say the h4
in this case actually has it inside of
it so h4 h4 is going to have margin
right
margin right
of let's say 10 pixels
very slightly push it away there we go
and on the right hand side we're going
to go ahead and fix that
okay so on the right hand side i'm going
to go ahead and do styled is something
called felipe this is actually called
styled components so style components
are very popular and i'd recommend
jumping in learning out how they you
work and stuff like that very very
useful stuff now here i'm going to
target
the the p element inside
do display flex a line item centrally
one size of 14 pixels i'm going to
target the p tag and the material ui
icon inside of it
and i'm going to go ahead and say margin
right 5 pixels and there we go and this
is how it looks on slack right so it's a
very clean at this point in time looks
very very nice at this point okay that
looks pretty good i think that looks
pretty good okay joshua says your css
skills are awesome man thank you so much
dude appreciate you
alright
so over at this point what we're going
to do is we're going to have the chat
over here okay so we've got the nice
header section complete okay so we've
got the header section complete the next
thing i want to do is actually go ahead
and add a sort of a sibling component to
the header now in order to do that in
react you're not allowed sort of two
components next to each other so if i
had something here for example it would
complain and say no no no you're not
allowed that so i'm going to have a
react fragment that wraps it
and then what i'll do is now i'm allowed
to have something next to the header all
right so what i'm going to do here is
actually have a
um a another
sort of a div called chat messages okay
so in this case we're going to just
create a uh
let's go ahead and do this to say
this is going to be chat messages
like this okay
and this one is going to be a style
component div so it's going to be const
equals styled div
there we go
and we can come to start that one
afterwards
all right so start div there we go and
inside of here what we're going to be
doing is we're going to be fetching all
the messages and this is where we would
sort of list out the messages
right so i'll show you how we're going
to do that in a sec
but in order to do that first we
actually need this little chat box where
we can actually send in messages okay
um deepak singh yes exactly it's about
typing yes boom you see it drops it over
there and that's the message right so
little message as well okay so what i'm
going to do is let's start the messages
so go back to our chat we need to create
a chat component here okay
so
there you go i'm going to make this a
drop smaller okay so i'm going to make
this like maybe a chance all right
that's pretty good all right so we have
the chat there so underneath all of this
okay so underneath the chat messages i'm
actually gonna have something called a
chat input right we actually have 570
likes guys come on let's keep going i
love it man honestly i can't i can't
believe it thank you so much guys we're
going to create a component called chat
input okay now chat input is going to be
our own little component we're going to
create and this is going to be
responsible for this magic okay and what
this needs is going to have a few
different things right so it's actually
going to have a channel name that we're
going to pass to it so we're going to
pass a prop which is going to be the
channel name and we'll sort of sort that
one out in a sec so we need the channel
name
and i need the channel id right now we
have the channel id this is just simply
going to be the room id now how do i get
the room id wait a sec we didn't have
the room id did we oh we did because we
pushed it inside the store now how do i
grab it from the store we use the
selector that i mentioned earlier
so if i want the room id i say const
room id and let's say equals use
selector this will allow me to pull a
value from the redux store okay so i
need to simply go ahead and import this
from our react redux and then what i do
is i get the select room id
selector that i wrote earlier and what
this does it allows me to pull the room
id from the store all right this will
mean i'm allowed to basically go ahead
and when i select the room you can go
ahead and do it bottle says you're doing
great sony thank you so much dude thank
you so much for everyone watching right
now appreciate all of you honestly right
so what we're going to do at this point
is we have the chat input which we need
to create so i'm going to go into my
components create component called chat
input.js okay
rfce
wait for it to pop in boom
and at this point i'm gonna go ahead and
say
const uh chat
input container
equals styled div all right this is
gonna be my style div
and i need to import
star components but again it's being
weird with the auto wing port so i'm
going to go ahead and manually do it
there we go and that this one is going
to be responsible for there we go all
right so this is going to be my div that
surrounds my chat input now for the chat
input screen how do we go ahead and
build this one out okay so for the chat
input screen i'm going to have a few
things inside of it it's going to have a
form okay so it's going to have a form
right
right um is anyone else obsessed to
learn everything from start or not the
whole progression of arts concept
karthik we actually cover everything
inside um you can use react context api
if you want but redux is gonna be the
professional one to use right so we're
gonna have a form inside the form we're
gonna have an input field okay now this
input field it's just gonna be a normal
input phone let's go ahead and say input
there we go oh god damn it right input
there we go
and inputs are self from closing so we
don't have that now the input is going
to have a placeholder right the good
thing about this placeholder is going to
have backticks because we're going to
have string interpolation so we're going
to say message
oops found
and then remember we passed in a prop
okay so string interpolation here allows
us to have a javascript variable inside
of our string so remember the props come
through here now we passed in a prop
earlier we passed in the channel name
okay so at this point i can get the
channel name
but we didn't actually pass in that
value okay instead what we did we passed
in the uh room id i think it was the
channel id we passed in so channel id
okay we passed that one in
right so at this point this one let's
just go ahead and say message room right
so for the mean time until i figured
that out okay marty says doing a great
job it's a fire thank you so much dude
for the input there we have it right now
what i'm going to do
is for the
buttons i'm going to actually have a
button and this button
i'm going to go ahead and grab a
material ui button yes i'm going to use
a material ui button
depicting yes right so here we've got
the button and then i went the buttons
have the text inside so i'm going to say
send
a message and this button is actually
going to be hidden right so i'll show
you what with the trick that we're going
to do here so this button is actually
hidden right and it's got type submit
and there's a reason why we do this
because if you have a button inside of a
form
and you have type submit when you type
in your input field and you hit the
enter key it will submit the button
right which allows us to have that sort
of cool functionality without the
visibility of a button and when we click
this button we're going to have a
function click off which is called send
message
okay uh karthik now i'm full time
teaching so i i do zero to four stack
hero by the way so zero to full secure
is the community that i built with the
papa fam first link in the description
two days left for the huge sale and then
we pretty much close the doors i don't
know why we're opening them up again
okay so it's a huge sale right now and
uh you guys can go ahead and enjoy that
if you want okay
so
uh don't blame me if you said something
i didn't know it ended because i'm
telling you now it's ending right so
there's a send message when you have a
button event it has something called an
event here we say e dot prevent default
because default when we have a form when
we hit enter on it it will refresh the
page we don't want that okay so this
will prevent the refresh prevents the
refresh from occurring oh yeah prevent
refresh okay
there we go
uh
right
so naruto i will answer that when we get
to it don't worry dude so okay at this
point we've got the chat input
okay
so now what i'm going to do is it says
chatting but it's not defined let's go
back to our chat and let's go ahead and
import chat and
all right so now if we refresh
okay so we've got the message room send
okay got itchy yeah ouch
all right
headphones get uncomfortable sometimes
there we go all right
so we've got chat input so at this point
you can see if i hit this and i hit
enter it would actually trigger off the
send button okay so
uh so what i'm going to do is for the
chat input let's go ahead and sort of
style this one out
right so inside of here what i'm going
to do is i'm actually going to target
the go into my chat input here
and we've got the star div okay so first
thing i want to do is i'm going to say
border radius to 20 pixels okay so i
want it to be a nice little border
radius behind it let's go ahead and do
this save
oops
border rate is 20 pixels and this will
give it a slight rounded corner okay now
i'm going to target the form and i'm
going to give it a bunch of properties
i'm going to say position relative
display flex and justify content center
the next thing i'm going to do is i'm
going to target the input form inside of
the form by doing this so we're going
inside the form
inside the input
right and then what i'm going to do is
i'm going to say position fixed bottom
30 pixels
width of 60 border 1 pixel border radius
3 pixels having a 20 and an outline of
none all of this will give us a nice
look and feel to this okay boom save
and if i go ahead and see that you see
that guys look at that it drops to the
bottom now this button is randomly over
here right but this is actually going to
be sort of you know
relative to where the screen moves right
because it's position fixed and it's
bottom 30 pixels off the ground and the
width is 60 pixels hence why it's 60
pixels this way
now what i want to do is i want to hide
that button so i'm going to target the
form target the button and say display
none and i'm going to make it important
so that way it just hides right because
it's material ui buttons sometimes you
have to override the styles save
and boom it disappears right now we just
get this nice functionality but if i
type in and i hit enter it will trigger
off my send message function
right if i get rid of this line the
prevent default one look what happens
if i hit enter see how it refreshed we
don't want a refresh right refreshing is
not our friend so that's why we don't
want it okay
so guys let's keep the energy up right
because if now we're about to hit 600
let's go
all right i'm going to go ahead and
change this one the rule says your
tutorials are giving me the confidence
to go out and apply for software
development jobs do it dude you got this
man and the papa fam's got your back
this is why i say to everyone join
honestly join join join this this is the
best community ever
right so at this point we have this
right now i'm going to go ahead and
upgrade this so we can fetch this
information okay so how do i go ahead
and do this now this is looking pretty
good at this point now i'm gonna firstly
add a message in and then we'll carry on
okay so
i'm gonna go into my
chat input
all right now let's go ahead and
implement the send message functionality
okay so the first thing i want to do is
i want to protect against any kind of
bug right now i'm going to say if there
is no channel id
right then i just want to return i'm
going to return first because i just
want to exit this this function i don't
want to do anything if there's no
channel id present okay the next thing
i'll do is i want to access my db okay
now the first thing before i carry on
actually is i've imported the db because
i'm going to need it i need to get the
piece of text from this input filled
okay so how do i do that i'm going to
show you a different way of doing it
this time when i say const let me show
you use refs i'm going to say input
reference
equals use ref so typically you've seen
me do it in a way where we map it to a
piece of state but this is another way
of doing it okay so we can go ahead and
import user f from a react and the way
we do is we save
and then here we go with another banger
let's go guys that's what i'm talking
about yeah and now what we do is we go
ahead and map this to this we say
reference to the input field is input
ref and you see it's just a lot cleaner
right it's a lot cleaner when we do it
this way and now what i'm going to say
is i'm going to go into the db dot
collection
okay i'm gonna go into the rooms
okay
and i'm gonna get the channel by going
into the document with the channel id so
think about what we're doing here
is we're literally going through
right well up and there
we're going into the the room itself the
document and then we're going into the
collection of messages okay so we're
going into the collection
of messages
and all i'm going to do is i'm going to
add a message in there because i'm
literally writing it in
right and then to do that what we do is
we simply go ahead
and we say okay the message i want to
add is message and the contents of that
message is i want to grab it from the
input field okay so how do i grab it
from this input field we basically say
okay
get the input reference get the current
thing it's pointing to
right and i'm basically going to go
ahead and get the value of it pretty
much that's it right that's how we do it
we get the value of the input filled at
that point okay
next thing we did shri khan thank you so
much dude shri khan's vengala for a
lovely five dollar donation appreciate
you dude thank you so much
right
now at this point we've got the message
now i need a timestamp just think about
it this way if i send a message in
london and you're based in new york or
asia or wherever it is my timestamp is
different to your timestamp so if we
both use firebase's firestores timestamp
then it's going to be the same so we can
sort our messages accordingly so how do
we do that right but firstly i need to
go ahead and import firebase
the actual firebase okay
and then what i need to do is go ahead
and say timestamp
all right timestamp and what i do is i
say at this point firebase dot
firestore guys almost to 600 likes let's
go why am i firebased on fire so i just
saw it and i was like oh my god that's
creeping we go to the field value and
then we say get the server timestamp
and then that's a function basically
that will give us the server timestamps
now all of our timestamps are the same
boom there we go 600 likes wow
like just wow man
a channel
we're getting like the same number of
likes as channels uh you know hundreds
of thousands of subs like
guys when we get to a hundred thousand
subs
oh ho the world better watch yourself
proper fans coming coming fast guys 20
likes just flew in like that
god damn this is what i'm talking about
guys
let's go all right so the next thing i
want to do is when i send a message in i
want to clear the text okay so the final
thing i want to do is go ahead and say
input ref
dot current
dot
value
actually what we can do at this point is
we can say
okay so you can do it this way right you
can do it this way or you can do it a
way of uh i've forgotten how you
actually clear it now deepak thank you
so much man so we can do it this way
this was a way of showing you i'm going
to show you right now the previous way
we're going to say equals value equals
input
and let's go and say input
[Music]
and this is how we initialize state
which is basically how we write a
variable inside of react
by default the input is going to be
blank and we say set input
all right
thank you so much dude for supporting
and then here what we say is instead of
this we go ahead and say input and what
we do is whenever we type in the input
field we say on change
[Music]
on change equals and this will give us e
and we say okay whenever the user types
in i'm going to set the input to a
e.target.value e.target
value oops oh e dot target dot value
like so save and what this will do is it
will means it means that we need to
import this
but that was just showing you an example
of how you can use references as well
i legally says you're doing a great
service i've been a react developer for
three years but i've learned a lot from
you appreciate it dude thank you so much
man uh moira says you are the goat let's
go man let's go dude
now what we're gonna do is here we have
the
um
input okay we've got that value input
here nice and then what we're gonna do
is we're gonna get the user's
information now we don't have the user's
information at this point oh
so right now i'm gonna hard code it as
sunny sanger
and then i need a user's image oh that's
even harder right how do i do that i'm
gonna go ahead and grab a picture of me
for now
[Music]
all right so i'm gonna grab a quick
picture of me
and let's see if nothing dodgy comes up
so i'm gonna grab my picture here
[Music]
let me grab a quick picture let's say
this linkedin one copy image address
make sure it's png that's not even a png
i hate when you get a fake png don't you
like you know you guys know what i'm
talking about when you get fake pngs
there we go i've got a jpeg there we go
all right so i've got a jpeg here it
doesn't matter you can use any picture
at this point okay so i've just popped
in a picture here
i'm gonna go ahead and come so now we've
got the user image okay so what i'm
going to do is i'm going to eventually
have it so when we log in it will pull
in that information right
um
okay so you can do ref or you can do the
other way guys it's completely fine
right um
there we go so and there are reasons for
each and all right but we're looking
against that right now okay so now at
this point what i'm going to do is have
it so that when i refresh right let's go
ahead and refresh and let's see now what
this will do is if we want to do is
we're going to say after we send that
message we're going to set the input to
empty okay done
so the input empty so now if i go ahead
and try this out save
and refresh okay let's get our firebase
up and running okay so we're in let's
say we go into the papa fan room and i'm
inside the public family and say abc
enter right oh did something happen did
it break what happened oh my god okay
let's have a look
so we're inside here
and nothing actually kicked off okay so
nothing kicked off let's go ahead and
see why
okay so i went into message input there
we go
unchanged value is input set input
target value message time sunny user
image there we go and refresh
okay let's go ahead and refresh and
let's say let me just double check my
terminal okay we're good and here i'm
going to say
abc
okay so right now something's actually
freaking out at this point uh there we
go cannot be called with an empty path
okay because the channel id there we go
it makes a lot of sense so
we need the channel id okay that needs
to be passed in so remember chat okay we
got the room id over here use selector
select room id so at this point what i
can do is i can actually just double
check that it gets passed through so i
can say console.log the channel id
right and then i'm going to go ahead and
refresh and i'm going to go and do f12
and then you can see the channel id is
no right now okay interesting if i click
this one now i've got a channel id
okay so with the channel id set what i'm
going to do is i'm going to type into
say test
okay
and i hit enter
right so i hit enter and nothing
actually happened okay which is very
very strange so let's go ahead and see
why because the channel already got
passed in here perfect okay let's go
over here
and what we've done over here actually
is we've said channel id is room id
perfect
okay
and let's refresh
all right
okay interesting let's have a look why
this is happening
document or collection rooms doc channel
id collection messages add
okay
here we go channel id
and we do have the channel id correct at
this point we're going into the room
and we should be adding into the message
is the input
timestamp is this timestamp the user is
sony sanger and the user image is this
okay
and what you need to do sometimes is
just cut the
this is a yarn start again okay let's do
this again
i do see the chat guys but i'm going to
block you if you keep asking me to speak
indie i'm not a pet okay let's carry on
all right
all right let's go ahead and wait for
that to restart so now what i'm going to
do
you can change the title in the
index.html if you do want to yes you can
do that
so now at this point if i go ahead and
say testing although we need to make
sure we click a pop-up fam so this goes
and we click paper fam i type in testing
enter okay so this is interesting at
this point right so if there's no
channel id it's returning first so let's
go ahead and double check at this point
when we hit send message if there is a
channel id
right
so
let's go ahead here and then let's go
ahead and say abc
enter oh there we go that's what i was
looking for and i'll be called with an
empty path okay so that's because i
actually went ahead and didn't click the
uh correct channel so papa fam
there we go and if i type in test and i
hit enter okay
so you see guys it did reach there but i
wonder at this point if it's actually oh
if it's not damn it guys if it's not
channel id there we go ah
i missed it good spot guys good start
there we go that's how you know i need a
water break
smash the thumbs up button for everyone
who got that right well done guys
okay now that's exactly what the problem
was
right so we're gonna click on paper fam
type in testing
boom and you see it disappeared perfect
okay so now at this point we're gonna go
ahead and check if we entered in as you
can see we should have in here
let's go ahead and see
let's refresh oh there we go it came
through uh it was a bit of a second but
let's go ahead and carry on that was
water dylan yes that was water
everyone thinks it's vodka
but let's go ahead in the top one we say
on messages alright so now you can see
the message has been successfully
entered into the room okay so that's
exactly what i was looking for so now we
have the collection here message
timestamp user and user image okay so
perfect we have a message there and the
channel name we need to go ahead and
pass in so how do we get the channel
name and all that good stuff set up okay
so inside of chat right now let's go
ahead and fetch the information that we
need okay so
first thing i want to do is get the room
details and then i want to get the room
uh the room messages so we can do this
actually really nicely all right so
using the new used collection i'll show
you guys how easy it is to do this all
right so here import use collection from
react fibers there we go we say cons
first thing i want to get the room
details
room details
okay so i get the room details and here
i'm going to say use collection
and then what i'm going to do here is
i'm going to say okay
oops if there is a room id present right
then i'm going to query the firebase
database i'm going to say db i need to
import db and say db.collection
uh yes deepak using pusher
right so db.collection i'm going to say
go into rooms and get the document with
the room id
okay so this will be the room details
all right this will go ahead and get us
that information okay so that's how we
do that in this case and then for the
room messages i'm gonna do is a similar
thing
um
i think it's my i might actually use
collection might be um let me check that
in a sec actually but yeah we're gonna
do this one and then what i'm gonna do
is i think it's use document instead use
a document
here we go use document yeah and this
one will be doc room id perfect and then
what i'm going to say is const i'm going
to get the room messages as well
and this equals use collection you see
how easy this is guys like this is crazy
man
like it's so much easier doing than the
traditional way that you're doing it
right you say okay only if there's a
room id
then i'm chill should i give you a super
chat oh [ __ ] dude all right it's up to
you man it's a db dot collection
and then i'll say rooms
dot doc and we'll say room id
dot collection
of messages so i'm going to go into the
messages
oops messages
and then what i'm going to do is i'm
going to go ahead and say
order by okay remember the time stamp
that we passed in we'll say order by
the timestamp ascending okay so order by
timestamp
ascending
okay
and then there you go so it's going to
order by the timestamp so now you can
see this will go ahead and give me the
room messages
plural and this will get me the room
details okay so how do i check this this
actually is doing what it says it's
doing if i go ahead and pop open this
and i go ahead and say console.log let's
just check the room details first room
details
let's go ahead and do room messages
save and let's go ahead and see now you
can see look chat 25 26 25 has given us
the data back this is actually correct
if i say
dot data
and now you can see that it gets us back
the room details so in this case if i
click on the room i have to make sure
i'm inside of a room so in this case if
i go into
papa fam you can see that it gets me the
papa fam room we're going to abc gets me
abc the room okay and same with the room
messages but this will be a collection
of documents so you can see it works
okay it comes through
now how do we pass this over into our
chat input it's pretty simple actually
the way we do it is we pretty much go
down to our chat input and then here
where we have channel name we pass in
room details
and it can be maybe undefined so we need
to do that and then we say past in the
name and now we pass through the room
name inside of chat input i can actually
get the channel name
and here i can actually say message
channel name so now what you should be
able to see is that by default it says
message undefined because we're not
inside of a room and we can fix that
afterwards but if i click paper fam it
will go ahead and it will actually pass
that through as the value now have we
correctly passed it through as a
question channel name there we go
lowercase c boom saved
right
and then let's carry on the guys we are
literally come on let's keep going we're
almost at 650 likes that's incredible
honestly i'm i'm a bit mind blown today
like
we had a tech issue we lost we had to
start from zero 650 people came in and
like that's just mad
all right let's go ahead and then click
on this and there you go look it says
message papa fam on the bottom left
message
there you go you see that if i click it
it changes over here message abc message
papa fam and i want the same thing to
happen over on the room name okay so for
the chat
uh there we go gamezone thank you so
much abdisrockshake oh i appreciate you
dude he goes the value you bring never
stops to amaze me just finish the
netflix and i see another build on the
way damn keep up the good work thank you
dude i really appreciate the kind words
honestly that sort of stuff keeps me
going so i really do appreciate it thank
you man
here we have the room name i'm going to
go ahead and do the same thing i'm going
to go ahead and pop into our jsx and
here i'll say roomdetails.data.name
okay so not data don't name let's go
ahead and hit save and let's do refresh
i remember by default it's going to be
undefined so it won't show any value
okay so we can go ahead and change that
afterwards
uh and then what i'll do is uh let's go
back to proper firm and you can see an
hour inside the pop-up fan room now
we're inside the abc room you see it
look works very very nice okay it works
very very slick right now at this point
what i'm going to do
is i'm going to go ahead and have it so
that we have
um let's just double check something i'm
going to go ahead and add so the
messages list up okay so we already have
the messages over here and what i want
to do is actually want to render through
those messages and actually sort of do
some magic with that so how do we do
that we go over here to chat messages i
go ahead open up my jsx and i say okay
let's go into the room messages
and it could be on can it could be
undefined at some point because it's a
async
it needs to fetch it i'm going to say if
every single document inside those
messages i'm going to have a bit of code
that runs okay and i'm going to
basically destructure that that message
and that has a message inside of it as a
timestamp remember when we push the
message in as a user and a user image
right and then this has doc.data so we
basically are pulling it apart from the
message um document okay
then what we're going to do is i'm going
to actually return
the following so i'm going to say return
and i'm going to basically create a
message component which is going to be
self enclosing and it's going to take
the following props so we'll have a key
because we're mapping through a bunch of
stuff
but what it's actually going to do
is this message component will take the
following information so it's obviously
going to freak out at this point because
it doesn't know what this message
component is okay so we need to go ahead
and create it so i'm going to grab
message go over here go to components
create message.js
save
do my little rfc trick wait for it boom
pop it in and then what we're going to
do is we're going to say const message
container right so message container
equals star div
all right start div boom boom and i'm
going to go ahead and pop this in now
the message container let's go over to
message i like this song
all right so i'm gonna go ahead and pull
in styled import start from style
components there we go and guys we are
literally near four likes away from 650
let's go come on we almost there so
message container now i'm gonna go ahead
and pop this in there
and then inside the message container
we're going to have a few things right
so we've already got a few things being
passed in so firstly i'm going to go
ahead and import this inside the chat
boom save
and there you go okay so now inside a
puppet phone we should have a message
here right but it's not actually being
rendered because we have nothing being
rendered here so firstly this takes a
few props like we just passed in so i'm
going to destructure the props and
inside we have the message the time
stamp and a few extra things okay so we
have message timestamp user and user
image okay message timestamp user and
user image three likes away let's go
guys
wow this is so sick man i can't believe
that we're actually going so fast uh
this one's not doing it for me let's go
ahead and change it uh you know what
let's try out the trending songs on
epidemic sounds alright so let's see if
that works actually no i'm not going to
risk anything let's go ahead and do my
songs
all right let's go ahead and do jump to
the bottom let's go ahead and do
something like
oh this one
okay
all right
so let's go ahead and say
650 oh nice there we go 56 50 likes
let's carry on guys wow thank you all
that's so cool man
all right so for the message i'm going
to have a few things on the image the
image source is going to be the user
image prop okay so the user image prop
and let's go ahead and save it and then
you can see that it pops through now so
if i add another message and say test
and make sure i'm in the correct chat
yes because every test remember it's
passing through as me right now there we
go okay uh there we go nice guys 700
come on let's hit i like target of 700 i
think we can do that man i think we can
do that all right
so let's go ahead and say
uh let's have a message info right so
message info container which i'm going
to create so this is going to be message
info which is going to be a similar
sort of div the styled component dip
message info
and then i'm going to go ahead and say
okay message info
and then thank you anchor appreciated so
here we're going to say h4 and inside of
that we're going to say user
and then i'm gonna basically have some
little kind of you know i'm gonna add a
jsx parentheses block and then we're
gonna say span
okay now i'm gonna span a few things
right please don't spam the chat dude uh
otherwise i'm gonna kick you out right
so here i'm gonna span and i'm going to
put in the following okay ayesha what's
up nice i don't see any chat
conversation in twitch it's not but in
uh in youtube it's going off pretty good
um
so now we get the timestamp right now
how do we change the timestamp that we
get from firebase into a readable string
and this is the line of code to do it
okay so you guys can maybe break this
one down in your own time but i'll
explain quickly it basically creates a
new date object from the timestamp we
need to convert it with this two-day
object which allows us to convert and
then here what i need to go ahead and do
is say two utc string so if i save it
now we should be able to see like sunny
sanger on this time spent sent that
message okay so it looks really good and
the next thing i wanna do is underneath
this i'm gonna have a p tag and the p
tag is just going to have the message
itself
okay so it's going to have the message
see like testing testing if i say abc
abc abc enter the message down here says
abc abc abc okay so it's very hard to
see that but you guys can see it's at
the bottom i promise it's there right so
the first thing i want to do is start
making this look like it's the way that
it should look okay guys we're almost at
70 honestly really almost at 70.
right um so what we're going to do now
is go into our message container right
so here
and i'm going to say display flex
right and then i'm going to basically go
ahead and say align item center align
item center
and then we'll say padding of 20 pixels
20 pixels okay and then here i'm going
to say go and target the image and make
the height of
okay
50 pixels
all right and then we'll say border
radius
[Music]
all right let's just say
water radius
of eight pixels there we go
okay and look at that pretty cool right
it's pretty cool right so now what we're
going to do is we're going to go ahead
and you see that's actually starting to
look similar to the sort of go that
we're trying to get to okay so we have
the image set so the next thing i'll do
is target the message info so i'm going
to go to the message info and say
padding left i don't want to touch that
next button okay so panning left of 10
pixels
you can use padding or margin there's up
to you i'm going to target the h4 and
inside the span tag i'm going to target
something we'll say inside the span tag
i'm going to do a color of gray font
weight of 300 margin left 4 pixels font
size 10 and this is going to make the
timestamp a lot smaller
there you go and it starts to look a lot
more like we wanted it to look at that
amazing stuff so this
is so dope
okay
that's pretty cool right really really
cool uh anshu please don't spam dude
um so at this point this is really
really good now if i click on abc and i
say hello can you see what just happened
there look it actually just changed
based on what i've got entered in here
and it will load up the messages inside
that room
and it just works just works so clean
that's amazing right it works really
really good really clean
okay now how do i get this though right
so if i go into a new channel
right if i go into a new channel how
does it automatically scroll to the
bottom and if i want to add a new
message so let's say testing
how do i get that look at that abc wow
how do we do that trick right so we want
to get that trick happening firstly you
need to smash the thumbs up button
joking i just had to do like a you know
what's his name uh graham stefan sort of
kind of vibe there oh let's carry on
right
look at the numbers going up man this is
crazy okay
all right so now what we're gonna do yes
this will be everything that's kind of
you're seeing now is going to be on the
channel after so it goes straight up on
the channel after so you can rewatch it
so at this point what i'm going to do is
we have the messages here okay so in
order to get that sort of auto scroll
functionality what you need to do is a
very neat little trick okay so we render
the messages over here okay so just
underneath the end of those messages i'm
going to create an a sort of a div
called chat bottom
okay so i'm going gonna create a div
called chat bottom and this is literally
just gonna be a div an empty div okay so
you don't even need to maybe have uh i'm
gonna give a little bit of padding to
the bottom though actually
so what i'm gonna do is i'm gonna create
a start component at the bottom so and
it's gonna have a panning bottom of 200
pixels and there is a reason why we did
that okay so
so wait for this to load boom
and there we go okay so now what i'm
going to do is i'm going to go ahead and
say chat bottom now what i need to do is
i need to give this a reference and i
will show you why because we're going to
do some pretty damn cool little trick
right now okay so
here we've got he's saying are you just
front and rear reactor does he have no
back and i haven't used firebase before
so right now this is actually more of a
front-end build the firebase powers
everything on the back handles it all
for us but i do do full stack
development yes so what i'm going to do
is chat ref i'm going to go to the top
and create a piece of reference so i'm
going to go ahead and get rid of these
console logs at the top i'm going to say
cons chat ref equals user f and i'm
going to go and say initialize it with a
value of no to begin with
okay now use ref we need to go ahead and
import that so i'm going to go ahead and
boom we import it from
react like so now to connect to my user
f to this i just go ahead and say ref
equals use rest and now i have a big
pointing at that the bottom of the chat
because think about it it maps out the
messages then we have an empty div at
the bottom and the reason why there's a
reason why we use this empty div
so
whenever this page loads i'm going to go
ahead and spam this chat right now
because i'm going to say hey something
like this right
there we go i'm gonna refresh and let's
see that we should have all of this
stuff popping
uh wait for it to load wait for it to
load wait for it to load
let's go into papa fam
it's just a bit slow right now but it
will work
okay there we go
nice so you see that that's just because
my internet right but can you see right
now how firstly we added the padding 200
so that way we can see the bottom and
the second thing that i wanted to do
guys is i wanted to so that when we go
on to like let's say we're on abc and
loads of messages if i go into papa fam
i want it to scroll to the bottom by
default okay so whoa ho
savann
thank you dude he goes really appreciate
your valuable content which is priceless
help me out to get my first freelancing
gig last year and you just dropped a
massive 27.99 euros that's like a dinner
tonight i'm gonna call that one so let's
go get some sushi thank you so much gwen
uh really really appreciate you dude
seven sorry sven thank you thank you so
much dude appreciate that man so the way
i'm gonna do this little trick is i'm
gonna have a use effect and the use
effect allows us to run a bit of code
when
the component mounts okay
so
use effects are written like such okay
so i actually cover this in my entire
full stack hero if anyone's watching an
interest in joining the papa fam two-day
cell empty it finishes in two days guys
first link in the description check it
out ff says sunny i've landed a job in
london at stores because of you dude
let's go for a beer man when london
lockdown's over let me know hit me up
all right so the use effect here right
we've already already imported over here
so i only want to sort of do it when
um
when the component mount as well as when
the room id changes okay so when the
room id changes
and what's really cool about these use
collections is they give you the loading
state and an error state i don't need
the aerostate but the loading state can
be handy here right so what i can
actually say here is that if the room is
loading this is firestore
right if the room is loading so if the
room is still loading with the loading
stage changes or re-fire this code and
what i want to do is i want to go to
that chat reference and i'm going to say
okay get the chat reference go to the
current thing you're pointing at and
scroll it into the view so save and what
happens is as soon as it loads it's
going to basically scroll me down so
this one it doesn't need to scroll down
but if i go to the papa fam watch how it
scrolls me to the bottom
boom scrolled me to the bottom
amazing works look really really nice
right it works right so
at this point and what you can do is you
can customize this with some really nice
little uh sort of additional extras okay
so what i can do is actually i can
actually add in this behavior smooth
right so if i go ahead and do this
behavior smooth now now look at this
guys if i go to abc and i go to the papa
fam it opens it up and it scrolls me to
the bottom now that's click
smash that thumbs up button that is damn
slick all right this is pretty cool
right that's pretty damn fun
all right now guys
if you're new to the channel you know
what to do subscribe it's going to be
big we're going to keep dropping these
bills but we're almost at 700 almost at
700 views right so let's carry on guys
700 likes sorry okay so what i'm going
to do now is every time i push your
message like look hello
see that oh it didn't actually throw me
to the bottom so i want to go ahead and
fix that so what i'm going to do is that
chat reference i had earlier i'm
actually going to go ahead and pass that
to my chat input
right as a prop so i'm going to say chat
reference i'm going to pass this as a
prop to
my
uh to the chat input right so chat ref
equals chat ref okay
so skier yes it would but this is sort
of those are additional features you can
go ahead and add on and things like that
you can obviously sort of you should add
lazy loading and things like that and
but this is sort of you know this is
enough for for uh one single bird okay
um so at this point chat ref okay we've
done that so we pass it through and then
i'm going to go ahead and grab it here
but good good couch
use my sql now i'm not using my sql uh
okay so at this point we've got the chat
reference here now what's cool right is
that when i go ahead and do chat input
because i passed it over here once i
send that message in all i need to do
now is basically go ahead and add do the
following i just say chat reference
dot current scroll into view same thing
but when i send a message inside of chat
input so now let's go ahead and check
this out
so let's go ahead and wait till this
loads up click papa fam and you can see
it should load up scroll to the bottom
and if i'm at the bottom over here and i
say
yolo
enter boom guys
look at that that's that's pretty damn
cool right it's a zero to hero course
live or video um so we have weekly live
coaching course dude so if you're
platinum you'll get a weekly coaching
call every single week if you're a
diamond you'll get a coach call every
week and then every fortnight an
additional coaching call which is pretty
damn intense so i'd recommend that but
platinum is the pack i recommend first
link in the description check it out we
also have the recorded content for the
modules so those are going to be
pre-roll coaching cool guys um that i go
ahead and do i record it and it gets
uploaded to the course so you get
honestly you get more and more content
as it goes and we also have a student
area where people publish games and all
sorts of stuff so
so sick honestly
let's hit 700 likes guys if you're
enjoying this right now smash that
thumbs up button uh it's crazy that we
have 134 people watching but we have
literally nearly 700 likes that's insane
really really appreciate you guys okay
so now what i'm gonna do
is i'm gonna go ahead and this is
actually working pretty good at this
point okay so now we're gonna go ahead
and do the authentication portion of
this build i think okay so if i go ahead
and refresh at this point you see like
it says message undefined and this sort
of stuff now
what i can do here is i can protect this
screen from showing this stuff if we do
not have this information okay and
that's a good idea i think to do right
so i'm only going to show any of this
stuff if we've selected a room right so
what i'm going to say is i'm going to
say okay only if we have the room
details
only if we have the room details and
if we have the room messages
should we then go ahead and load up this
all right this is a better practice to
have and this will basically go ahead
and protect so you see that right so now
we don't get anything in this we click a
channel and then it go ahead and uh it
goes ahead and loads it that's a lot
cleaner okay that that really looks a
lot more cleaner when we do that okay so
um
let's carry on so
the farm there you go
um nice this looks really good oh nice
kush says i use your slap videos
reference to build my real estate
website that's oh that's actually really
cool dude i'd love to hear more about
that
i'm getting into real estate myself now
okay carry on guys
so at this point we're going to go ahead
and implement the login authentication
and then we're going to refactor so that
these are actually pulling in your names
and we're going to go ahead and deploy
this bad boy and you guys are going to
be able to jump on this app and try it
for yourself so it's gonna be so sick
right let's do this i know the music is
sick i swear it's like becoming like a
coding dj i swear my i don't care my
music playlist for coding is the best
it's like the goat of all of all
playlists for going i don't care i'll
say that
it's clean man all right so at this
point i'm gonna go ahead and let's
imagine how do we set up a login system
okay so if we go into app.js this is
where the magical begins okay so app.js
is where everything sort of starts off
from so
so now what we're going to do is go
inside of app.js now this is really cool
okay so before we had to use use
something called on auth status right
and things like that um
that was why yes so what i'm going to do
is but now we have the handy react hooks
okay so i can go ahead import use auth
state which is a really cool hook and
this one is so damn good because what we
can do is we can say const user look at
this if i go ahead and drop this line of
code in this gives me the user it gives
me a loading status
and
you get the and all you need to do is
pass it the authentication and the
authentication we prepped earlier inside
of our local firebase file so if i hit
save on this now we should have the user
inside of our app.js now what's really
cool about this guys is that what we can
do is we can say okay
inside the router right inside the
router over here
if we have so if inside the router here
if we do not have a user then show a
login screen okay then show a login
screen
else and this is kind of a protected
route now because else it will render
the app okay so it will show the login
screen if you if there's no user present
it says login is not defined makes sense
so we need to go ahead and create the
login so here what i'm going to do is
i'm going to go ahead and create a login
component login.js boom
pop that in rfce
and guys almost at 700 likes this is
insane let's keep going and here i'm
going to say const login container
equals style.diff
boom boom like so i'm going to go back
to my app.js
over here my login do my import
there we go vlog we just imported it and
then what i do
open up login.js and then in here i need
my styled components so i'm gonna pull
them in
and i'm gonna have my login container
over right here perfect and there you go
we have a login right and it's not
working yet we're almost there though
all right so login container right
inside the login container i'm actually
going to have an inner login container
right so i'm going to log in
in a container and i'll make sure i'll
show you why we do this it's going to
help us out in just a sec
okay so at this point what i'm going to
do is and guys we are three likes away
from 700 let's go wow aisha's ice is
there hey what's up aisha
all right let's go guys
all right so now log in in a container
what we're going to do here and the
reason why we see a white screen is
because we do not have a user that is
inside okay so what i'm going to do is
i'm going to have the image and this is
an image of slack i'm going to pop an
image of slack in there and we should
see uh login in the container is not
defined so boom there we go 700 likes
700 likes
and we have a hundred and so a hundred
and
forty people watching across platforms
that is insane thank you guys
thank you so much wow
darwin rather a small really smart thank
you so much dude honestly thank you so
much for for donating i really really
appreciate anything that's really
honestly kind of you
look at that guys the slack logo that's
huge i don't like that the slack logo
okay so um let's carry on so what i'm
going to do with the login in the
container i'm going to target that image
and i'm going to make it smaller
immediately so that way we can start
seeing things all right so here i'm
going to say okay target the image
i'll get the image and then i'm going to
say okay object fit contain to keep the
aspect ratio
object fit contain and then i'm going to
go ahead and say height of 100 pixels
right over 100 pixels i don't even care
this slack this slack build is damn dope
margin bottom of 40 pixels and then save
and boom look at that looks fresh right
now for the logging container over here
what i'm going to do is i'm going to say
okay let's give it a background color a
height of 100 view height display grid
and place item center this gives it a
very nice extra sort of it will center
the element like so that looks pretty
clean
looks good all right looks good now for
the inner container what i'm going to do
is i'm going to go ahead give it padding
of 10 100 pixels a text align center
background color is going to be white
and i'm going to give a border radius of
10 pixels and i'm going to show you a
little cool trick okay so at this point
you guys can see it's got a nice little
border radius and it looks okay right
but i'm going to show you how crazy
small tweaks are in css i swear to god
can we hit 750. 800. i swear we're going
to keep on growing i don't know where
these likes are coming from thank you
keep on just smash the thumbs up button
if you're enjoying this but guys fabian
van dyke yes you won in the challenge as
well do you appreciate you so guys check
out this little trick right very small
differences right so this is a very
subtle box shadow you can just copy but
look how amazing the effect it has right
so a box shadow is about to be dropped
look at that i swear to god like look a
tiny little difference and all of a
sudden the whole ui is clean now
all right so this is really cool uh
redirects can protect you but this
actually sort of protects you at a much
stronger level because it just it
doesn't even load the component in the
first place a redirect there is a moment
where it kind of catches you then
redirects you okay so i wouldn't i would
say do it this way
to be sure now what we're going to do
we're going to reach them yeah i don't
know how to pronounce that one but a
good gazillion likes um so now what
we're going to do is inside of here
we've got the image and i'm going to go
ahead and say let's have a div of login
text we're going to have some login text
here okay so i guess what we can do is
remember we have a h1 okay and then
we're going gonna say sign in
sign in to the papa fam
okay and then underneath that i'm gonna
have a p tag and this p tag is gonna
have a p not please i'm gonna say
papa.slack.com something like that now
guys just to shout out we do have a
slack community it's pretty damn cool we
have over 220 or 30 members now inside
of the papa fam sac community to join
first link in the description go ahead
check it out we're running a huge sale
right now papa fam has each other's back
it's just the best community you guys
seeing the energy right now it's so cool
honestly i said let's go ahead and hit
save and you can see sign into the
pop-up fan there we go
and then what i'm going to do is i'm
going to have a material ui button okay
now the material ui button is going to
say sign in with
google okay sign in with google like so
and then i'm going to hit save
and now what i'm going to do is say type
submit
type submit
like so and then what i'm going to say
is on click
i unclick and i'm going to basically
trigger off a sign in function
okay now i need to create this sign in
function so firstly i need to import the
button from material ui core so i'm
going to go ahead and do this
and then i'm going to go ahead and say
this
where is it material material material
ui uh there we go save and then the sign
in function i'm gonna go ahead and say
consignment
const i'm gonna say const sign in equals
e
boom boom and say e dot
like so okay like this
and then what i'm gonna do is i'm gonna
say okay now this is where the fun part
comes in okay so look it's got a sign in
with google bond but that looks a bit
trash at the moment okay so this button
looks ugly right and i'll admit it does
not look nice okay so
what first thing i'm going to do is i'm
going to go in here i'm going to target
the button all right i'm going to say
okay the button should have a margin top
50 pixels and i'm going to do a few
things i'm going to make the text
i'm going to change the transformer text
change the background color to a green
because by default everything is
uppercase so it's going to be it's going
to be a lot better right jay says sunny
the true beast jay we're nearly like 750
likes dude and the whole thing like
crashed oh my god we're just killing it
today all right let's carry on guys um
all right so at this point um what we're
gonna do
is oh okay so if there's no form yes
you're right you don't need the button
type submit i did have a form there
before for something else that's why i
had that so good catch uh samuel that's
what i look for man that's what i look
for right so uh naruto thank you so much
for tuning in i'll see you soon dude so
here we have the sign in now how do we
get a google i've already done a halo
club before i'm gonna drop down the
channel though so how do we get the
google sign in okay so google sign is a
lot easier than you think smash the
thumbs up button if you want to find out
all right so we're gonna go ahead and do
it right now i'm swearing the guy's
gonna be like
how many of you think i can implement
the entire google login in like one line
of code right one line of code right one
line of code right are you ready for
this one line of code is gonna do the
whole google login are you ready for
this this is where it's just like
unbelievable power right so here i'm
gonna say auth
i'm gonna pull in my auth from my local
firebase i'm gonna say sign in with
pop-up
boom okay
then i'm gonna go ahead and pass in the
pop-up now the pop-up is the provider
that we set up earlier okay so it's a
provider remember we actually pulled
that in from our local firebase file so
i'm going to go ahead and pull that in
and then i'm going to say okay that's
all good and then i don't need to do
anything after i've signed in i'm just
going to make sure that i catch any
errors okay so if there is an error i'm
going to alert the user of the error
i'll say error.message
right okay pretty cool all right let's
just let's go ahead and see if this all
works right i mean like that seems a bit
too easy to be to be true right
so i'm gonna go ahead and hit sign in
with google okay
pretty cool remember you need to you
need to enable that on the the the
firebase platform i'm gonna go to the
paparat team account
and
boom
that was it
that was it we are literally logged in
right now which is in crazy crazy stuff
right and what's so cool about this is
that if i go to app.js literally guys
this is doing all the hard work for us
right now this right here is doing
everything for us um i'm actually gonna
go ahead and let's see let's let's start
some new suggested tracks
oh my god okay
let's do this all right can we hit 750
likes god this is the papa fam anthem i
didn't even realize i was about to play
that that's yeah right
so i'm gonna go ahead now and get the
user's information i'll show you how
easy it is without having to use a lot
of readout stuff okay so are you guys
ready all right now what we're going to
do is we're going to go into the header
and start implementing or using the
user's information where it's needed all
right this song gets me so hyped up this
is when we first dropped announced the
papa fam
this is where that vibe comes this is
what it's all about right this is what i
try and communicate in these videos
that's what we do guys all right so now
we're gonna do is go over to header
and then we're gonna jump into
alex says what is this playlist what is
the song
this is like the papa fam anthem dude
this is called don't want to sleep by
swift 7th
and we don't want to sleep here dude we
do not want to sleep so header avatar
right so i'm going to go into my
header
and i'm going to go ahead and say okay
i'm going to basically go ahead and say
[Music]
hey i'm going to say okay the source is
going to be
oops the source is going to be
the user and it could be undefined we're
gonna say the photo url okay photo url
like so and then what i'm gonna do is
i'm gonna actually gonna have the
alternative as well it's gonna be the
users displaying it now how do i get
these values okay so remember we can
actually just pull this in using that
neat little use auto state hook from
firebase
now that's as simple as it is honestly
that gives us the user and it just works
papa found the movie i like that i like
that dude what about the movie can you
imagine that holy crap
i'd watch that
i'd literally watch it i'll be the one
that someone will be acting
right
i'm gonna import there we go safe
mama says loving this ah there she is
all right so now you can see we sign in
now
there's an issue with that right because
the sources use a photo url and it
didn't work
right so at this point what i want to do
is firstly i want to go ahead and make
sure that this is all done correct so
let's save let's refresh
and the header right interesting so the
source isn't actually being passed in as
we wanted it to
and this is because we have header
avatar this is using the correct avatar
one so boom
hover pointer start avatar avatar is
over here material ui call done cool
okay so i'm going to go ahead and make
this very easier to read so we can see
it and then what i'm going to do is i
actually want to make the avatar have on
click will actually go ahead and do an
anonymous function in line inline it'll
use the authentication and just
basically calls a sign out function
which actually signs us out of the app
so with that alone we should actually
have everything we need okay so oh man
this is another one that we had this is
literally all the songs that we had when
we first dropped it honestly it touches
imagine christopher nolan directing a
movie on paper react oh my god that's so
funny you said that that's amazing dude
all right so i'm going to click this and
it should log us out there we go okay so
it did log us out all right so we need
to figure out why i'm not getting that
picture come through right that's the
main issue that we have right now so if
i do proper react or team
let's go ahead and see it should log me
in and we should see it come through
okay so now what i can do is to quickly
debug this it's fine we can go ahead and
say console.log and just say user is
user
and then let's go ahead and see what's
happening in the in the terminal user is
here we go and here we've got a bunch of
stuff
photo
url
ah that's why okay so it's user.photo
url so for the photo url it's capital
right popper is emotional now it's crazy
right
[Music]
so that's why
and there you go look there it is
perfect all right that's amazing now at
this point we've got proper fan we can
click here and what i want to do is i
want to send that message as sunny but
not through like a hard-coded value okay
so what i want to do is i'm going to go
to my chat input and remember where we
sent that message earlier we sent it
with hard-coded values here okay so now
we don't want to do hardcore dude
because why do we need to do hardcoded
because we actually have the actual
thing working okay so this is clean i'm
not even doing this a really clean code
right now okay so what i'm gonna do now
is we've got the user being passed no we
haven't we've got the uh i need to pull
the user in at the top so i'm gonna go
ahead and pop the user in like so
and i'm gonna go ahead and pull the hook
in and the hook does it very efficiently
so it's gonna make sure it uses it once
and it just reuses it car says go thank
you so much dude let's hit let's hit
likes man let's go ahead come on i think
we can hit 750 dude i seriously think we
can do it
okay so at this point what we're going
to do is we're going to go ahead and do
auth is not defined we need to import
off there we go save refresh like that
okay and then the user's name okay so
for the user's name i'm going to go
ahead and say
user.displayname
for the user's image i'm actually going
to go ahead and say rather than that one
was a user.photo url and the best part
about this is we're just getting this
information straight from firebase
so boom if i go ahead and say proper
farm and i go and say yo
what's up
boom look at that guys if i say abc
it even scrolled me down
that's clean
i don't even care what anyone says that
is so clean that he's like
he's like i'm proud of that dude that's
actually a really really good build like
that's the kind of like uh the sort of
you know you want that to be you want
your code to be that level of like
spotless right so that's like i swear i
was proud of that one guys 11 likes away
from 750.
okay so at this point we have
our app working in the way we expected
it to okay everything works in a nice
way here we can add channels let's go
and say uh let's just say like uh
it's a youtube channel okay let's click
on youtube and then let's go ahead and
say
yo what's up youtube
and you can even put emojis in says drop
a fire emoji oh oops my
up in the
file
oh okay i guess my rocket crashed yo
what's up youtube there we go and it
works right so that looks pretty good
all right so i'm gonna go ahead deploy
this in a sec and then we're actually
gonna go ahead and do this right does
firebase hook some reactions do the same
because it actually allows you to go
ahead and it uses a use effect under the
hood i actually teach inside of zero to
full stack hero how to create your own
hooks really really fun exercise as well
that we do inside the course remember
guys two days two days left inside of
our sale and then we close the doors to
the community and i don't know when
we're opening up again but all i know is
that the energy is untouchable like it
is the best like that's it period
right so at this point pretty good i
think everything here is actually
perfect in the sense of besides that i
almost missed that the sidebar
okay
so the sidebar at this point the sidebar
at this point has got a hard-coded name
we don't want a hardcoded name we want
the actual name of the user so what i do
is i just pretty much go ahead and grab
the user
and again if we're not using this oh i
actually have another feature on to do
the loading state so if i forget remind
me okay carl says really like that
scroll to bottom yeah really really cool
addition now here what i do is i go
ahead grab the user like so save not
defined yep i always missed that one
wait for it and let's go ahead and
import this and guys by the way if you
do want access to this code and you feel
lazy then the second link in the
description is the link to the papa
github repo where all of this is
available now i want to address
something now did you notice how what
happened just there i had refreshed the
page i was logged in already so if i go
ahead and refresh here i'm already
actually logged in
but what's up andy b you guys can't wait
to watch this back later yeah oh yeah
dude this really really fun build
actually so you see when we refresh
right there's a loading there's a point
where it's loading and it's not actually
sort of it hasn't got the user yet all
right i want to have it so it looks a
bit like this so look imagine if it
could look something like this
that's pretty clean right that's
actually pretty clean and i want to get
that working so how do we get this
in play right because that's clean as
well right so what i'm gonna do juwan
says hi sonny thanks for the amazing one
i'm really learning for the first time
after years thank you so much dude um so
what we're to do now is inside of app.js
right here all right so in app.js so i'm
going to go to app.js and then here we
have everything happening we have the
sort of you know the user notification
stuff but what i'm going to do now
is actually have it so remember we
pulled the loading station so i'm going
to say okay
if it's loading
all right then i'm going to return a
different bit of jsx oops not that
yeah if it's i'm going to return a
different bit of jsx now i'm going to
create a uploading so i'm going to
create a uploading container so this is
going to be a div and inside of it i'm
going to have uploading contents another
div
okay so i'm going to have another div
and we're going to quickly go ahead and
set those ones up
okay so i'm going to do uploading
let's go ahead and chuck those at the
bottom let's go ahead and do this to say
cons
uploading
same there we go we've got uploading and
then we've also got the second one which
was app loading contents
these are two styled components and let
me know hit the thumbs up button if you
like
the um
part is when you can get mine if you
really like style components i am a fan
honestly and we didn't even use the most
powerful thing like the props use case
right so it's actually extremely really
powerful sunny best the best go go go
appreciate it dude five likes away from
750 wow oh man and you see we didn't
even actually make full power of a
reactor we didn't actually use much of
reactor so you don't actually fully need
it
but you guys can i i implemented it
because i want to make it so you can
extend on it and by having
place you guys don't have to ask you
know how do we have it inside of this we
just you can pretty much use it okay so
what i'm going to do now is i'm going to
go ahead and say now where we have this
um
i'm going to go ahead and pop in here
and then what i'm going to do is inside
of here i'm going to have an image and
this is the slack logo now that cool
little spinner that you just saw this is
a snack logo by the way so oh
go ahead and see something okay
something looks ugly and this is because
i have not done this one oh there we go
ah
scared me for a sec all right so you see
now there's a huge logo that's kind of
stuck in the beginning right so we're
going to fix that in a sec
but what i want to do is that um
sunny programming seems so complicated
in a good way thank you so much dude um
so here i'm going to actually install
something called react spin kit okay so
you guys can check out their docs their
docs are really cool actually and
they're very simple the way they explain
it they show you a bunch of examples but
it's this guy right here carl matthews
and he actually shows the use cases in a
demo screen if you want to check it out
but right now i'm going to show you how
to implement it okay come on j to pull
it up and say yarn add react spring kit
we're going to go and install that now
once we've installed that while it's
doing it i'm going to import spinner
import spinner from react spin kit
and then what i'm going to do one
microwave whoa our sign law says
something i'm 11 years old can i join
the zero to four stacker of course yes
dude we have 12 year old in there we
have a 14 year old in there two 14 year
olds in there there's no age limit
751 likes that's what i'm talking about
wow like wow that's just like
unheard of level of craziness like how
we get so much support is just unreal i
don't care man we we don't have
a hundred thousand subs yet and we are
crushing channels with hundreds of
thousands of subs so
we're killing it dude
killing it so now let's go ahead and say
at spinner like so and then we're gonna
go oh no that's horrible spinner
and
then up there we go nice let's kick you
up a bit spin up and then here i'm going
to go ahead and say okay
the name of the spinner is this one you
can get the names from the demo page and
i would recommend checking it out right
finn says that is so sick that's what
i'm talking about dude i'm gonna color
purple and fade in of none but split
second so i don't want any animation i
just want to pop straight into you have
to say none okay i'm gonna save
goblin says i did three projects from
science channel and i've got an offer of
1500 euros a month but sadly gonna make
kind of fun around dude well done
firstly okay that's all it's all about
face to rejection
that's a good thing right now the next
interview you have you're gonna crush it
i trust me and if it's not that one
you'll crush the next one but it will
happen it'll come and you'll walk into
that interview one day saying you know
i'm just i'm ready for this man and that
confidence will come through we teach a
lot of this inside the course but it's
really like honestly anonymous group
says i'm gonna keep this energy up
that's it dude keep this up man
all right
upstairs i was waiting for you dude
finally you're back i hope you can
continue making videos regards thank you
so much dude appreciate you um so at
this point now we've got the if loading
so now okay let's go ahead and refresh
you see it pops up while it's loading
but we need to style it now okay so what
i'm gonna do here is i'm going to go to
my uploading and i'm actually going to
make this look a bit cleaner so i'm
going to go ahead and jump on a few
things um adam says i've actually
started
penning these builds out physically
instead of building them straight away
so i can concentrate on why the code is
used more i've learned so much dude
that's incredible that's what i'm
talking about man that's exactly what
i'm talking about
so
look you want to check in text align
center padding bottom 100 pixels display
flex flex direction column justify
content center align item center now
while you're styling this you don't want
to keep refreshing and kind of guessing
okay so what i do is i go to here and i
say if true
while it's doing while i'm sort of
working it out right so if true and then
it will kind of force the screen to stay
on right and then i'll just make sure
you don't leave it like that they say
image i'm gonna say a height of 100
pixels
i'm going to say padding of 20 pixels
i'm going to save it i'm going to say a
margin bottom of 40 pixels now as well
okay so margin 40 oops margin 40.
and let's go ahead and refresh
oh no wait a sec
this is actually this should be in the
other container this should be over here
i got it mixed up we should chuck this
one in the actual contents there we go
and you see that guys look that's the
actual loader okay
please share your working experience i
do inside the coaching calls i think we
can complete hit that said it oh hit
that i think we can hit 800 likes let's
do it man if we can break eight hundred
people in this video man crazy right
anonymous group says something i kill
this build exactly exactly that's what
i'm talking about right so i want to add
a margin bottom because right now it's
touching it okay so what i'm going to do
here is i'm going to go to the bottom of
this and say margin bottom for you and
it will drop it a little bit away nice
now how do i get this to center out okay
so i'm going to do display grid place
item center height of 100 view height
and a width of 100 on the uploading
container okay
boom save
and there you go okay now we've got this
little loader okay now what i can do is
i can change this boolean back to
loading so it's no longer forced to true
and i hit save all right and now check
this out guys are you ready for this
boom loading
while it's loading it's gonna be here
and then when the user comes it'll go
ahead and pop us in that's clean i don't
even care that's so clean it makes me
excited like you can tell i i can't fake
this level of excitement right i know
it's geeky i don't give a crap like that
is a geek out moment i was just like on
the other day like this stripe checkout
team jumped into the netflix challenge i
blew my mind when i saw that the actual
stripe checkout team were in the chat
that's insane man i couldn't believe
that
so this is uh styled components not
regular css we're just doing start
components and it has a lot of pros and
cons there's a lot of pros sorry a lot
of pros okay so i'm gonna go ahead and
save and now look at this guys we hit
refresh
boom nice perfect right and then you
click on the channel and there you go
that is so slick that's really really
nice right so at this point
guys i think we are i think we're ready
to deploy this app are you guys ready to
deploy this let me know let me know
right now are you ready to deploy this
application to firebase
and go ahead and uh yeah get this thing
working
right
let's go ahead and do this guys smash
the thumbs up button if you're excited a
new pum please stop spamming dude yes
i've already built that
right vikram says i'm ready dude that's
it
anonymous group dude i'm gonna have to
time you out dudes please don't do that
all right
well i think is it yes so we got
everyone getting ready for this nice
sunny isn't necessary to learn to tell
when css
um i mean it's a new trendy sort of
thing i'd say right um all right so
everyone's ready for this right so i'm
going to show you how to go ahead and
deploy this okay so
let's find a quick let's find a nice one
there we go let's just bring this up
this is good
so to deploy your app right so what
you're going to do is you're going to go
ahead and pop up in your terminal
and here i'm going to go ahead and say
firebase login so the first thing you
want to do is log in okay now i've
already logged in so i don't need to do
this but you need to go ahead and say
firebase login first the next step is
going to be firebase init okay now
firebase init basically goes ahead and
sets up your application with firebase
okay so this is just a huge terminal
right now so what we're going to do here
is i'm going to go ahead and go down
with the arrow keys to hosting okay now
you can see you've got a bunch of other
stuff here but we're interested in
hosting today so we're going to click
hosting on the spacebar and enter now
you're going to click use an existing
project okay so i'm going to click that
and then we should see a list of our
projects inside of this account right so
at this point the one that we created
right now was actually going to go ahead
and say you guys can see all these
builds that i've done it's crazy uh
right now we have the slack clone right
and this slack clone youtube all right
so i'm going to go ahead and hit that
one and then here what do you want to
use as your public directory this is
extremely important do not mess this up
all right if you do do firebase in it
and do the whole step again right but at
this point
what you're going to do is and guys in
the meantime i wonder if we can break
800 likes by the time we deploy how
crazy would that be let's do it if we
finish it we'll finish this on such a
high man oh in the public direction
we're typing build okay so it's going to
be build right so i'm going to hit build
and then configure it as a single page
app yeah so you're going to click yes
with a y okay so undo this boom save and
then set up automatic bills and deploy
we get up no we're not going to do that
and then it sets up okay the next step
yes you guys have started guessing it
right now we're gonna do mpm run build
or you can do yarn build it doesn't
really matter at this point right but
npm run build now important step what
this does is it basically goes ahead and
there's loads of things when we build
our like hot reloading and a bunch of
other stuff right we don't always need
that in the final production build we
don't even need in the final production
build because our customers aren't
developers they just need the fastest
app so we basically trim out all the fat
of the app and then we basically go
ahead and
create an optimized production build and
as you can see here it says pretty much
we're going to go ahead and create an
optimized production build so once this
is done it will basically bundle up our
application into a lovely folder over
here called build okay now something
important to know you do not touch the
build folder pretty much okay so you
don't really mess around with the build
photo and instead the way you need to do
it is that if you touch any of your code
after it's gone ahead and finished
bundling remember you need to run mpm
run build again because it it would be
your build would not have the latest
changes inside so you if you change your
code you need to go ahead and do npm run
build again and then it will work and by
the way guys i hope you liked that
proper match it's pretty cool just
sweating in the camera right so now what
we're going to do
is we're going to go ahead and say we're
almost 300 likes oh my god just keep
going smash that like button if you're
enjoying this so now we do it we did a
big moment guys we're gonna go ahead and
hit that button right so i'm gonna go
ahead and drop a track right let's do it
all right guys we're gonna do that we're
gonna say firebase
deploy
all right
and this is about to deploy this app
to
firebase right so it's found the folders
in the build folder
and it's uploading the folders and it
will give us a url in just a sec and i
will go ahead and share that url and you
guys can go check this out i released it
and it gave it hosting url boom that's
what i'm talking about guys i'm gonna go
ahead and drop that in the chat right
now and we have a fully functional
application right now go ahead and check
it out let's go ahead and see this out
right now guys let's see this
check it out guys
and look at this it's loading for me i'm
signing in let's go ahead and check out
go ahead check out let's see if we can
do this
and you know what i think it's only
right i think it's only right that we
have one song that does this one right
so go ahead proper reactor team i'm
gonna jump in on my account right here
and there you go right i'm going to go
in the proper fam chat who's going to
meet me in the papa fam chat
[Music]
yo what's up guys
yo look at this
[Music]
look at that guys everyone's popping in
what's up vikram look at this guys
oh man this is so sick
[Music]
how cool is that guys
that's so sick alright it's working
manuel says i'm playing the same song
here hey that's it guys
look at that ayush's chat all right
we've got abc we got the youtube chat
i got youtuber here i was first
how cool is that guys that's so
so powerful
incredible incredible stuff
let's do a overview of what we built
today right so somebody said there's an
overscroll error on the sidebar yes
there could be an overfl scroll error on
the sidebar uh remember if we what can
happen there is you can basically
truncate if it is an issue or you can go
ahead and do something else but you can
go ahead and remember we built this
entire app in three hours guys i'm
incredible so yes if there's a tiny
little bug somewhere we'll fix it that's
fine it's all good final bird in the
papa get up repair now a few things to
mention guys let's go ahead and say we
have two days left to join the proper
farm first link in the description thank
you i said you've done a great job today
guys we do this kind of stuff all the
time inside the course right now and
it's honestly the best right we go ahead
we crush it we do incredible builds we
do coaching calls well i just sit down i
break the stuff out with you part of the
papa fam zero to full stack hero is live
it's crushing we have over 230 members
strong right now
check it out the first link in the
description okay and this is me saying
it to you because i have a huge sale one
right now and if you guys want to get a
part of that then it's going to end in
two days and i don't want that out
because i'm going to be closing the
doors to the internal proper farm after
those two days up again honestly really
don't i'm going to focus on everything
uh suddenly you're getting faster and
faster with this type of clone thank you
so much thank you and thank you uh
gerard thank you so much from ivory
coast amazing stuff vikram says this
project was so good uh guys this is
incredible play is on that no
thank you so much guys and i wanted to
say um yeah just feel free to hit the
thumbs up button and share the video out
let's get this video to as many people
as possible remember our goal with the
papa fam is not to just like create cool
stuff and it's a lot of fun yeah it's a
lot of fun but guys we're here to change
lives like my goal is to really help you
guys change your life right it's in like
land a job go ahead and just become a
better more dedicated person and that's
what i'm trying to do with these birds
that's why the papa farm exists that's
why we do what we do and i just want to
say thank you to everyone who was a part
of today's build who was here and if
you're watching the replay thank you so
much and i appreciate you and i want to
say guys today we built an incredible
app together we built a really really
incredible app and uh it honestly it
works so so amazing and somebody i okay
we've got a little error over there
where it kind of overflows that's fine
though
we have this incredible app i'm gonna
show you my one local one
and uh yeah guys this is absolutely
insane we built the slack clone and the
code is available in the second link the
link to the papa github repo is
available that's also on sale i mean
that's going to be coming off sale very
shortly and fantana says sunny love this
appreciate you thank you so much guys
and uh mohammed says have a great
weekend that's it guys i want to say
have an amazing weekend this video had
redux react firebase hooks and it was a
complete overhaul of the previous slack
cone it's so goddamn powerful it's so
good now clean and we guys we topped it
off with start components so again thank
you so much for watching and i hope you
guys have an amazing weekend this is
your boy
papa react signing out i will see you
guys
in the next video guys
peace i appreciate all of you honestly
really really crazy stuff thank you dear
and i'm just gonna give i'm gonna read
these comments as i always do as we tune
out today but guys thank you so much and
i will see you in the next video peace
[Music]
me
hey
[Music]